Augur: a Decentralized, Open-Source Platform for Prediction MarketsDr. Jack Peterson & Joseph Krug www.augur.netAugur is a trustless, decentralized platform for prediction markets. It is an extension of Bitcoin Core’s source code which preserves as much of Bitcoin’s proven code and security as possible. Each feature required for prediction markets is constructed from Bitcoin’s input/output-style transactions.I. INTRODUCTIONA prediction market is a place where individuals can wager on the outcomes of future events. Those who fore- cast the outcome correctly win money, and if they fore- cast incorrectly, they lose money. People value money, so they are incentivized to forecast such outcomes as accu- rately as they can. Thus, the price of a prediction market can serve as an excellent indicator of how likely an event is to occur [1, 2]. Augur is a decentralized platform for prediction markets.Our goal here is to provide a blueprint of a decentral- ized prediction market using Bitcoin’s input/output-style transactions. Many theoretical details of this project, such as its game-theoretic underpinning, are touched on lightly or not at all. This work builds on (and is intended to be read as a companion to) the theoretical foundation established in [3].1A.TradeSports – over the past decade has shown, if govern- ments or special interest groups want to shut down a web- site, they will find a way: InTrade, after all, was an Irish company, shut down as a result of the U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commissions actions [5, 6]. Even the Defense Advanced Research Project Agency and Central Intelligence Agency were forced to end their foray into prediction markets as a result of Congressional interfer- ence [7].Contrast this with the history of Bitcoin [8]. Bitcoin is a cryptographic currency and payment platform that has found an enemy in powerful nation-states and finan- cial institutions. Nevertheless, Bitcoin has thrived: as of November 2014, it has a market capitalization of over five billion U.S. dollars, and it is the anchor of a thriving ecosystem of startups, trade, and technological innova- tion. This is possible because Bitcoin is decentralized: once it was released, it could not be shut down. Even its pseudonymous creator, Satoshi Nakamoto, cannot stop the cryptocurrency. This is by design: he (or she or they) purposely did not make himself Bitcoin’s single point of failure.Augur is a decentralized prediction market platform. The Augur Project’s goal is to revolutionize prediction markets, and, in doing so, change the way that people receive and verify ‘truth’.B. StrategyAugur is built as an extension to the source code of Bitcoin Core.2 It includes the features – the betting and consensus mechanisms – required by prediction mar- kets. However, it is intentionally the same as Bitcoin in all other respects, to capitalize on Bitcoin’s security and scalability. Our intention is to use the ‘pegged sidechain’ mechanism to make Augur fully interoperable with Bit- coin [9]; if this technology is not available, we will instead use our own internal currency as the store of value.C. TokensAugur has three types of tokens or units. To keep track of these units, every transaction input and output value2 Alternatives, such as smart contract-based implementations, are discussed in Appendix B.Why decentralize?Historically, the actions required of a prediction market – accepting wagers, deciding on the outcome of an event, then paying the wagers back out according to the results – have been centralized. The simplest approach to aggre- gating wagers is to have a trustworthy entity maintain a ledger. The simplest way to determine the outcome of an event is to get the answer from a wise, impartial judge, whom all participants in the market trust.Upon closer inspection, these straightforward answers fray at the edges: who is this ‘someone’ who is trustwor- thy enough to maintain a ledger for everyone else? Who is the judge that every participant trusts? And, even if such paragons were found and agreed upon, how could participants be certain they will remain trustworthy once they are granted more power? “Opportunity makes the thief”, after all. And, of course, “Power corrupts. Abso- lute power corrupts absolutely.” [4]In practice, a larger issue is that these trusted entities represent single points of failure. Prediction markets are often disliked by powerful interests. As the experience of centralized prediction markets – such as InTrade and1 Additional details and discussions on the theory behind Augur can be found at www.truthcoin.info.  
Event included in marketEvent happens!2  BEFORE THE EVENT: FORECASTINGBetting           Event createdMarket opensEvent(s) mature               User encrypts report and broadcasts      ReportingConsensusQuorum reachedReports decrypted   AFTER THE EVENT: REPORTINGReputation updates & BTC payouts      FIG. 1. Simplified outline of the actions in a prediction market, separated into before and after the event.fields is accompanied by a units field.Although there are three types of tokens, users have asingle cryptographic private key.3 Augur addresses are simply base-58 hashes of their cryptographic public keys, to which users can send tokens. The different types of token are distinguished from one another solely through the ‘units’ field. Therefore, users sign the transaction data of a Reputation payment in exactly the same way as they would sign a Bitcoin payment.The first token is Bitcoin. Sidechains allow us to transfer Bitcoin by creating a transaction on the Bitcoin blockchain that locks up the Bitcoin in an address [9]. Then a transaction is made on our blockchain with an input that has a cryptographic proof that the lock was made on the Bitcoin blockchain along with the genesis blockhash of its originating blockchain. A simplified pay- ment verification (SPV) scheme is used to verify these locks. A SPV has a list of block headers for proof-of-work and cryptographic proof that the locking transaction was created on one of the blocks in the header list.A key feature of Augur is tradeable Reputation. The total amount of Reputation is a fixed quantity, deter- mined upon the launch of Augur. Holding Reputation3 Augur uses the same public/private key cryptography system as Bitcoin: private keys are random 256-bit numbers, with a valid range governed by the secp256k1 ECDSA standard.entitles its owner to report on the outcomes of events, after the events occur. Reputation tokens are similar in other respects to Bitcoins: they are divisible to eight dec- imal places, they are accounted for by summing over un- spent transaction outputs, and they can be sent between users.A significant way that Reputation differs from Bitcoin is that Reputation is not intended to be a stable source of value: Reputation tokens are gained and lost depending on how reliably their owner votes with the consensus. Reputation holders are obligated to cast a vote every time the network ‘checks in’ with reality (by default, this is every 8 weeks). Another significant difference is that Reputation is not mined. Instead, Reputation will be distributed by means of an auction, as proposed in [3]. This solves two problems. First, it will provide fund- ing to complete the development of the Augur network. Second, it bootstraps the network with an initial group of Reputation-holders who are invested in the network’s success.Using a Bitcoin sidechain is a straightforward way to purchase shares. Users will simply transfer Bitcoins to the Augur network and use them to buy shares of a prediction. However, this poses a problem. If two peo- ple want to make a wager on whether event X will oc- cur within a year from now, they would be exposed to the price volatility of Bitcoin. A potential solution is a seigniorage modeled coin. This would create a new Event Event Event Event Event
cryptocurrency, say ‘USDCoin’, and put them on a few exchanges to be traded. If the price were above one dol- lar, the coin algorithm would print more coins; if below a dollar, the algorithm would discontinue printing. This allows the price of the coin to stay relatively close to a dollar.4Another pertinent question is how to distribute the coins used to buy shares of predictions. A few options are available: 1) having a Bitcoin sidechain be the mecha- nism to buy shares, 2) using a seigniorage model to create a ‘Cashcoin’ or ‘USDcoin’ that maintains its value with respect to the US Dollar, and 3) using a hybrid approach of 1 and 2.In our view, the best option is to sidechain Augur to Bitcoin, and have a new seigniorage based coin to al- low users to both wager with Bitcoin, and another cur- rency which would be used more for longer term wagers in which volatility would become an issue. This provides the benefits of allowing interoperability with Bitcoin holders as well as a currency suited for holding shares of predic- tions.II. PREDICTION MARKET CREATIONThe life of a prediction market can be separated into two principal ‘phases’ (Fig. 1): before and after the event. To walk through the life cycle of a typical prediction mar- ket, consider a user, Joe, who wants to wager on the outcome of the 2016 U.S. Presidential Election.A. Event CreationJoe turns on his Augur program, which plugs him di- rectly into the peer-to-peer network, and clicks on the ‘politics’ group. This brings up a list of all active polit- ical prediction markets, along with their current prices. No one has created a market for the 2016 election yet, so Joe decides to take the initiative. He clicks on ‘Create Event’. Here, he enters the necessary information about this event (Fig. 2):• Description: a short description of the event.• Type: binary (yes or no), scalar (numeric), or cat-egorical• Range of valid answers: yes/no/maybe for boolean, the minimum and maximum allowed values for scalar.• Topic: the category the event falls into. Topics are created by users, and can be as fine-grained as users want them to be – examples might be ‘politics’, ‘sci- ence’, ‘funny cat videos’, ‘serious cat videos’, and so on.4 See Nubits for an example.• Fee: a small fee (on the order of 0.01 Bitcoin) re- quired to create an event. Half of this fee goes to users who Report on the results of the event, after it happens (details in Section IV).• Maturation: duration of the forecasting phase. This is the period where users buy and sell shares of the market. In Augur, time is marked by the block interval, which is expected to be constant, on average. Users have the option of entering a ‘block number’ (which is exact, but not intuitive) or an ‘approximate end time’ (which is not quite exact, since the block interval is not always exactly the same length, but is much more intuitive).• Creator’s address: the address of the event’s cre- ator.CreateEvent TransactionJoe pays a fee of 0.01 Bitcoin to create this event. As shown in Fig. 2, this is the CreateEvent transaction’s only input. The CreateEvent transaction also has a single output, which contains the event’s data.The output’s data includes the event’s automatically assigned unique ID, which is a 160-bit hash5 of the other event output fields. To prevent accidental duplicate event creation (due to network latency), the same user is not permitted to create the same event again, with the same expiration date and description. The value of this output is the user’s event creation fee. The output can then be spent by including the event in a CreateMarket transac- tion (see below).These inputs and outputs are combined into a Bitcoin- style transaction:6{"type": "CreateEvent", "vin": [{}], "vout": [{"n": 0,"value": 0.01000000,"units": "bitcoin", "scriptSig": "<Joe’s signature><Joe ’spublickey >"3 5 6SHA256 followed by RIPEMD160, usually referred to simply as ‘hash-160’.Like Bitcoin, Augur’s transactions are broadcast and stored in serialized form. A deserialized, rawtransaction-like JSON format is shown here for readability. For brevity, fields such as locktime and sequence are omitted from our examples when they are not directly relevant. Also, for Script fields (such as scriptSig and scriptPubKey) only the asm subfield – i.e., the input to CScript() – is shown. 
FIG. 2. CreateEvent transactions are payments from the user’s address to a newly-generated event address. A CreateMarket transaction is a coinbase for shares of all the events contained in the market. Any user who has created one or more Events can incorporate their event(s) into a new market. In this simplified diagram, arrows represent inputs and outputs, and lines represent spending an unspent output. Note that events and markets have been given simplified IDs (E1, E2, etc.) here to make the figure easier to read; actual event and market IDs are 160-bit hashes of the event or market data fields, respectively."n": 0,"value" : 0.01000000, "units": "bitcoin", "event": {"id": "<event hash >", "description": "Hillary Clintonwins the 2016 U.S. Presidential Election.","branch": "politics", "is_binary": True, "valid_range": [0, 1], "expiration": 1478329200, "creator": "<Joe’s address>"},"address": "<base-58 event ID>", "script": "OP_DUPOP_HASH160 <event hash > OP_EQUALVERIFY OP_MARKETCHECK"<event hash> OP_EQUALVERIFY OP_MARKETCHECKSince the event ID is the hash-160 of the Event’s data, the CreateMarket transaction’s matching input Script is:4      BTC (from Alice)CreateEventCreateEventEvent: “Hillary Clinton wins the 2016 U.S. Presidential Election.”Binary: YesTopic: PoliticsValid Range: [0, 1]Fee: 0.01 BTCMaturation: November 5, 2016 Creator: JoeEvent ID: E2CreateEventCreateEvent PaymentBTC (to E1)                     BTC (from Joe)BTC (from Bob) BTC (from Chris)BTC (from Tom)BTC (to E2)BTC (to E3) BTC (to E4)BTC (to Joe)BTC (from E1) BTC (from E2) BTC (from E3) BTC (from E4)BTC (from Joe)CreateMarketTitle: “Joe's bizarre bazaar” Events: [E1, E2, E3, E4] Loss limit: 10 BTCTrading fee: 1%Funding: 27.72588722 BTC Creator: <Joe's BTC address> Market ID: M1∞ shares (to E1) ∞ shares (to E2) ∞ shares (to E3) ∞ shares (to E4)BTC (to M1 pool)                                                  }]}The raw event data is supplied by the user to be included in a market, then is pushed onto the stack during the sub- sequent CreateMarket transaction. OP MARKETCHECK first calculates the hash-160 of the market’s fields (excluding the market ID), then verifies that this hash matches the actual market ID. The CreateEvent transaction’s output is automatically sent to the event’s address, which is a base-58 string derived from the event ID in the same way that Bitcoin addresses are derived from the public key’s hash-160.B. Market CreationOnce the event is created, he then clicks on ‘Create Prediction Market’, where he can include his new Event in a prediction market. Here he enters other information about the market:• Title: label/brief description of the market.• Events: list event IDs to be included in the market.The CreateEvent output’s Script is keyed to the Event’s ID:7OP_DUP OP_HASH1607 Transaction Scripts are conventionally written left-to-right. However, we use a top-to-bottom format here for the sake of readability.<market <market <eventhash >data > data > Coinbase for shares of all predictions in the market
• Funding: up-front funding provided by the mar- ket’s creator, which covers the creator’s maximum possible loss in this Market. This is calculated us- ing the loss limit, a parameter specified by the user.• Loss limit: this parameter is set by the market’s creator. The loss limit (l) sets the maximum amount of money the market’s creator can lose if the number of shares goes to zero:"n": 0,"value": 27.72588722, "units": "bitcoin", "script": "OP_DUPOP_HASH160 OP_EVENTLOOKUP OP_ISSHARES OP_MARKETCHECK"maximum possible loss = l × log Nout(1)"n": 1,"value": 10ˆ9,"units": "shares", "event": "<event -1 hash >", "branch": "politics", "script": "OP_DUPNout refers to the number of outcomes, across all events, in this market. Greater values of l translate to greater market liquidity, but greater potential loss for the market’s creator.• Creator: the address of the market’s creator. CreateMarket TransactionAs shown in Fig. 2, the CreateMarket transaction has an input and an output for each event included in the market, plus one additional input and output for the user’s Bitcoin payment, which provides the market’s ini- tial liquidity. If NE is the number of events included in the market, then the CreateMarket transaction has NE + 1 outputs:1. The market’s input funding is sent to a special mar- ket pool address, which is a hash of the market’s data fields.OP_HASH160 OP_EVENTLOOKUP OP_ISBITCOIN OP_MARKETCHECK"2. There is a coinbase output for each event that is included in the market. These coinbase outputs create an essentially unlimited number of shares for eachevent.8 Includinganeventinamarketspends the event transaction’s fee output, so that it is no longer available to be included in other markets.This is stored in a transaction as follows:{"type": "CreateMarket", "loss_limit": 1.2, "vin": [{}], "vout": [{"n": 0,"value": 27.72588722,"units": "bitcoin", "tradingFee": 0.005, "scriptSig": "<Joe’s signature><Joe ’spublickey >"}, {}, {}, ...],"id": "<market"creator": "<Joe’s address>"}The tradingFee field is the transaction fee to buy or sell shares in the market. This is specified by the market’s creator, and is expressed as a multiple of transaction vol- ume. Here, Joe has set tradingFee at 0.01, so traders in this market will pay a 1% fee. These fee payments are divided in half, and split into two Buy and Sell transac- tion outputs each: one sent to the market’s creator, and one sent to the market pool.The locking Scripts for the CreateMarket outputs are somewhat different than those used by Bitcoin:OP_DUPOP_HASH160OP_EVENTLOOKUPOP_ISBITCOIN (or OP_ISSHARES) OP_MARKETCHECKThe purpose of Bitcoin locking Scripts is to verify that the recipient controls the private key associated with the public key hash recorded in the Script – that is, that they are the legitimate owner of the unspent output. By con- trast, to spend shares (or Bitcoins) from the CreateMar- ket outputs, the requirement is that the sender supply (1) the event ID (hash) of which they are Buying or Selling shares, and (2) the number of shares or Bitcoins which they wish to trade."n": 2,"value":"units":"event":"branch": "politics", "script": "OP_DUPOP_HASH160 OP_EVENTLOOKUP OP_ISBITCOIN OP_MARKETCHECK"10ˆ9, "shares", "<event -2hash >",hash >",5 8 Our initial implementation will include 109 shares per event; this can be increased later if needed.
OP EVENTLOOKUP ensures that the target event ID matches one of the events in the market. OP ISBITCOIN verifies that the units field in the unlocking input Script is bitcoin; this instruction is in the Script for the shares outputs. Similarly, OP ISSHARES verifies that the incom- ing units field is shares, and is in the equivalent Script for the market pool (Bitcoin) output.Happy with the market, Joe then publishes it. This deducts the l log NE market funding payment from his account, and broadcasts his CreateMarket transaction to the Augur network. Miners can then pick up and include this transaction in a block like any other transaction. Once it is incorporated into a block, and attached to the blockchain, Joe’s Market becomes visible to all users of the Augur network.III. BEFORE THE EVENT: FORECASTINGJoe’s prediction market has now been created. When the market is first created, the events contained in it have not yet occurred. This is the forecasting phase. It lasts from the time the market is created until the expira- tion specified by each event. Typically, event expiration should coincide with the occurrence of the event: Joe’s event is set to expire at midnight on November 5, 2016 (recorded as a Unix timestamp, 1478329200).In this phase, the market’s participants are forecasting or predicting the outcome of the event by making wa- gers. The way that they make these wagers is by buying and selling the outcome’s shares. In this section, we first discuss market making, then delve into the details of the Buy and Sell transactions.A. Market MakerReal-world prediction markets have often had prob- lems with liquidity [10]. Liquidity is an issue for pre- diction markets, because, generally, a market’s forecasts are more accurate the more liquid the market is [11]. To avoid the liquidity issues that arise from simple order books, we instead use the logarithmic market scoring rule (LMSR) [12, 13].The LMSR is the market maker for the entire mar- ket: all buy and sell orders are routed through the LMSR, rather than matching buy and sell orders between traders. The key feature of the LMSR is a cost function (C, in units of Bitcoin, or BTC), which varies accord- ing to the number of shares purchased for each possible outcome:C (q1,q2,...,qN) = llogwhere qj denotes the number of shares for outcome j, N is the total number of possible outcomes, and l is the6 loss limit, which is determined by the market’s creator.When the qj ’s are all zero,N e0 =N =⇒ C(0,0,...,0)=llogN. (3) j=1This is the maximum possible loss.The amounts paid by traders who buy and sell sharesin the market are the changes in the cost function caused by increasing or decreasing the total number of shares. The cost to the user to buy x shares of outcome k is the difference between the cost of the new set of shares outstanding and the old:C(q1,q2,...,qk +x,...,qN)−C(q1,q2,...,qk,...,qN) If a user wants to sell x shares of outcome k, the cost tothe user is the difference:C(q1,q2,...,qk −x,...,qN)−C(q1,q2,...,qk,...,qN)Since this difference is negative, the user receives Bitcoin from this transaction, in return for shares. The current price for outcome i (p (qi )) is the derivative of Eq. 2:   eqi /l p(qi)= Nj=1 eqj/l.(4) N where a and b are the lower and upper bounds on the scalar’s value. Although the integral in Eq. 6 cannot be evaluated analytically for unknown q(x), good model ex- traction and numerical approximation methods exist [14– 17].B. Buy and Sell TransactionsNow that Joe’s new market is active, anyone can buy shares of it using Bitcoin. Another user, Paul, looks up eqj/l , (2) j=1A more in-depth discussion of the LMSR, and the equiv- alence of prices and probabilities, is in Appendix C.Special CasesEq. 2 covers events that can have arbitrary, categorical outcomes. Our other two event types are special cases of Eq. 2. Binary events are simply categorical events with only two possible outcomes. For binary events, the cost function simplifies to:Cbinary (q1 , q2 ) = l log  eq1 /l + eq2 /l   , (5)If we restrict our attention to events with scalar out- comes, the exponential sum in Eq. 2 becomes an integral:Cscalar (q(x)) = l log   b a eq(x)/l dx , (6)
FIG. 4. Sample Report. Reputation owners report on the actual outcome of an event, after the event has occurred. Each ‘Your Report’ entry is initially set to NO REPORT ENTERED; if submitted that way, the user will not receive credit for reporting on that event. INVALID reports are permitted – in fact, encouraged! – for poorly-worded and/or indeterminate questions, since truth-by-consensus works well only for outcomes which are easily and objectively determinable. Since this user’s Reputation is 42, his/her ballot has a weight of 42. Another user who has a Reputation of 105 would also only cast a single ballot, but his/her opinions would be given 2.5 times as much weight as the first user’s.There are a few unusual things about the Report trans- action. The first is the structured quorum field:"quorum": { "matured": true,"reported": 0, "required": 2, "met": false}There are two requirements for quorum to be met:1. The events being reported on must have passed their maturity time. Typically, if people are re- porting on an event, this will be the case – events’ maturity times should be set at or after the (ex- pected) time of occurrence. In this example, the Report transaction has been made after the matu- rity time, as expected.2. The minimum number of required reports must be met. In this simple example, there are only two re- ports required to meet quorum, zero of which have been provided so far.10Once quorum is met, the market closes, and no more Bitcoin transactions are accepted. Report broadcasting continues for a pre-specified period of time. Upon com- pletion of this phase, each Report is decrypted, and the Reports are gathered into a report matrix. This matrix10 Not counting the current report, which has just been broadcast to the network, and is not yet included in a block.has users as rows and events as columns; the values of the matrix are the users’ observations.The other unusual feature of the Report transaction is its output Script, which includes several new commands:OP_DUPOP_HASH160<Jane ’s hash -160> OP_EQUALVERIFY OP_DATACHECK OP_CONSENSUS OP_PCACHECK OP_EQUALVERIFYThe first, OP DATACHECK, calculates the hash-160 of the Report’s fields (excluding the report ID), then verifies that this hash matches the actual Report ID. This is to ensure that the transaction’s contents were not tam- pered with during the delay from the time the Report was broadcast until the market closes.The second new command, OP CONSENSUS, initiates the consensus algorithm, which is described in detail in the following section. OP CONSENSUS requires the report ma- trix as an input. The report matrix does not yet exist when the reports are first broadcast; instead, it is pieced together when the Reports are decrypted. Once the re- port matrix is assembled, it is written to the associated input’s scriptSig.OP PCACHECK verifies that the outcome of the con- sensus algorithm is correct.11 The final opcode,11 The consensus algorithm is a modified form of a common statis- tical technique called PCA (Principal Component Analysis) [18],9  Reputation: 42  Event Your Report  Hillary Clinton will win the 2016 U.S. Presidential election.  NO The unemployment rate will be lower at the end of 2017 than at the end of 2016.   YES  If Hillary Clinton is elected President in 2016, the unemployment rate will be lower at the end of 2017 than at the end of 2016.  YES  Hillary Clinton sucks!  INVALID      Submit Report      
FIG. 5. Report and Redemption transactions. In this simple example, there are only 2 users reporting, Helga and Jane. (In reality, their names would not be known.) Helga broadcasts her report first, after the event has reached its maturity date. Since she is the first user to broadcast her report, only 1/2 users have reported, and quorum has not been reached, so the markets associated with the events listed on the ballot remain open. Later, Jane fills out her ballot and broadcasts it. At this point 2/2 users have reported, and quorum is reached. This automatically triggers the Redemption transaction, which makes use of special commands in the Report transactions’ output Scripts to reach and verify consensus. Notice there are actually 3 users total; the third user, Beatrice, neglected to submit a Report, and therefore lost Reputation.OP   EQUALVERIFY, compares the product with the original (centered) report matrix and ensures that they match.2. Redemption TransactionThe Report output’s matching input Script is as fol- lows:" n " : 1 ,"value": 42,"units": "reputation", "scriptSig": "<Jane’s public key><Jane ’s<report<centered report matrix ><centered <all outstanding shares>,reportmatrix >"},<all outstanding "vout": [<all reputation >,<all wagers >]}wagers >],<report matrix >10       10 Reputation (from Helga)42 Reputation (from Jane)BTC (from Paul) shares (from E2) BTC (from Joe) shares (from E2)Report Report ID: R1 Outcomes: <encrypted> Matured: yesQuorum: no (1/2)Report Report ID: R1 Outcomes: <encrypted> Matured: yesQuorum: yes (2/2) Quorum met!Buy Event ID: E2Outcome: YesBuyEvent ID: E2 Outcome: No10 Reputation (to R1 pool)42 Reputation (to R1 pool)BTC (to E2)shares (to Paul) BTC (to E2)shares (to Joe)10 Reputation (from R1 pool) 42 Reputation (from R1 pool)shares (from Paul) shares (from Joe)BTC (from E2) BTC (from E2)Redemption Report ID: R1Events: [E2, ...] Outcomes: [yes, ...] Updated Reputation:19 Reputation (to Helga)37 Reputation (to Jane)4 Reputation (to Beatrice)BTC (to Paul)                                                      User Reputation Helga 14 Jane 45 Beatrice 4                                                         {public matrix >key >The centered report matrix is the report matrix with the per-column weighted mean subtracted from each column. This Script is found in the Redemption transaction (Fig. 5), a special transaction which is initiated whenquorum is reached:The Redemption transaction is quite large: it has two inputs for every outstanding wager – one for Bitcoin, one for shares.12 Reputation balances are updated using a modified version of the Sztorc consensus algorithm [3].13 This algorithm’s purpose is to reward users whose re- ports are consistent with the consensus, and punish those whose reports are not.Per-share values are fixed according to the consensus- determined outcomes. The fixed share-price values are then used to determine the payout sent to all users hold- ing shares in these events. Payout values are assembled in a matrix containing the events in columns, and the12 Various hard-coded size limits on transaction and block size are lifted specifically for the Redemption transaction.13 Details of the consensus algorithm are shown in Appendix A."type": "vin": [{}, {hence the name OP PCACHECK."Redemption","n": 0,"value": 10,"units": "reputation", "scriptSig": "<Helga’s public key><report matrix ><centeredreportmatrix >"   
share owners’ addresses in rows. When this payout ma- trix is complete, the market broadcasts it to the Augur network. Once it is incorporated into a block and added to the blockchain, the payouts appear in the recipients’ accounts.[1] C. Manski. Interpreting the predictions of prediction markets. NBER Working Paper No. 10359, 2004.[2] J. Wolfers and E. Zitzewitz. Interpreting prediction market prices as probabilities. NBER Working Paper No. 10359, 2005.[3] P. Sztorc. Truthcoin: trustless, decentral- ized, censorship-proof, incentive-compatible, scal- able cryptocurrency prediction marketplace. https://github.com/psztorc/Truthcoin, 2014.[4] M. Felson and R.V. Clarke. Opportunity makes the thief: practical theory for crime prevention. Police Research Series, Paper 98, 1998.[5] U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission. CFTC charges Ireland-based “prediction market” proprietors Intrade and TEN with violating the CFTC’s off-exchange options trading ban and filing false forms with the CFTC. Nov. 26, 2012.[6] M. Philips. What’s behind the mysterious intrade shut- down? Bloomberg Businessweek, Mar. 11, 2013.[7] P.F. Yeh. Using prediction markets to enhance us intel- ligence capabilities: a “standard & poors 500 index” for intelligence. 50, 2006.[8] S. Nakamoto. Bitcoin: a peer-to-peer electronic cash sys- tem. https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf, 2008.[9] A. Back, M. Corallo, L. Dashjr, M. Friedenbach, G. Maxwell, A. Miller, A. Poelstra, J. Timon, and P. Wuille. Enabling blockchain innovations with pegged sidechains. http://www.blockstream.com/sidechains.pdf, 2014.[10] C. Slamka, B. Skiera, and M. Spann. Prediction mar- ket performance and market liquidity: a comparison of automated market makers. IEEE Transactions on Engi- neering Management, 60:169–185, 2013.[11] D.M. Pennock, S. Lawrence, C.L. Giles, and F.A. Nielsen. The real power of artificial markets. Science, 291:987– 988, 2001.[12] R. Hanson. Logarithmic market scoring rules for mod- ular combinatorial information aggregation. Tech. Rep., George Mason University, Economics, pages 1–12, 2002.[13] R. Hanson. Combinatorial information market design. Information Systems Frontiers, 5:107–119, 2003.[14] J. Shore and R. Johnson. Axiomatic derivation of the principle of maximum entropy and the principle of min- imum cross-entropy. IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, 26(1):26–37, 1980.[15] J. Skilling. Data analysis: the maximum entropy method. Nature, 309:748–749, 1984.[16] S. Presse, J. Lee, and K.A. Dill. Extracting con- formational memory from single-molecule kinetic data. J. Phys. Chem. B, 117:495–502, 2013.[17] S. Presse, J. Peterson, J. Lee, P. Elms, J.L. MacCallum, S. Marqusee, C. Bustamante, and K. Dill. Single moleculeACKNOWLEDGMENTSThe authors thank Vitalik Buterin, Paul Sztorc, Zack Hess, Alan Lu, Joe Costello, Jeremy Gardner, Casey De- trio, Joe Dolinak and Kinnard Hockenhull for their in- sights and feedback. Financial support for this project was provided by Joe Costello.conformational memory extraction: P5ab RNA hairpin.J. Phys. Chem. B, 118:6597–6603, 2014.[18] J. Shlens. A tutorial on principal component analysis.http://arxiv.org/abs/1404.1100, 2009.[19] G.R. Price. Extension of covariance selection mathemat-ics. Annals of Human Genetics, 35:485–490, 1972.[20] V. Buterin. Ethereum white paper: a next generation smart contract & decentralized application platform.https://www.ethereum.org/pdfs/EthereumWhitePaper.pdf,2013.[21] G. Wood. Ethereum: a secure decentralised gen-eralised transaction ledger, proof of concept VI.http://gavwood.com/paper.pdf, 2014.[22] E.T. Jaynes. Information theory and statistical mechan-ics. Physical Review, 106(4):620–630, 1957.[23] E.T. Jaynes. Information theory and statistical mechan-ics II. Physical Review, 108(2):171–190, 1957.[24] Principles of maximum entropy and maximum caliber in statistical physics. Reviews of Modern Physics, 85:1115–1141.[25] J. Shore and R. Johnson. Properties of cross-entropyminimization. IEEE Transactions on Information The- ory, 27:472, 1981.11 
The algorithm outlined here is a modified version of the Sztorc consensus algorithm, originally presented in [3]. In the original algorithm, the first eigenvector of the covari- ance matrix (the principal component) was solely used, regardless of the amount of variance it explained. Our modification is that a fixed fraction of explained variance is specified. This should make the rewards/punishments for reporting with/against the consensus more consistent across different Branches.Suppose there are E total events being reported on by N users. We first take the ballot B of votes and con- struct its weighted covariance matrix, where the weights are Reputations. The centered ballot (the ballot with each event’s weighted mean value subtracted out) X is:X=B−1rTB, (A1)where T denotes the transpose operation and the dif- ference is taken per-column. The ordinary (unweighted) covariance matrix is given by multiplying the centered data matrix and its transpose; similarly, the weighted covariance matrix is [19]:Σ=XTRX, (A2) 1− Ni ri2where R has the elements of r on its diagonal and zeros elsewhere, Rij = δijri.Each row (and column) of Σ corresponds to the vari- ability across users, within a single event. Since there are E events, Σ is an E × E matrix.Next, we diagonalize Σ,Σ = SΛST , (A3)revealing Λ, an E × E matrix with Σ’s eigenvalues on its diagonal, and zeros elsewhere: λ1 0 ··· 0  0 λ2 ··· 0 Λ= . . .. . . (A4).... 0 0 ··· λEThe eigenvalues are in descending order, λi > λi+1.The eigenvectors of Σ are the columns of the simi- larity matrix, S. The column of S associated with the largest eigenvalue (λ1) is called the principal component, s1. This component s1 is a unit vector oriented in the direction of as much of the report matrix’s variability as can be captured in a single dimension. This direction of maximum variability might be thought of as a hypothet- ical user who maximally contributed as much as possibleto the variability in this particular set of reports.The projection p1 of the centered data matrix (X) onto the principal component s1 tells us how much each user’s reports contributed to this direction of maximumFIG. 6. Non-conformity scores plotted against users’ change in Reputation after a single ballot resolution, in a small ex- ample of 50 users reporting on 25 events. The sizes of the circles indicate the number of users submitting identical re- ports. Blue indicates honest users; red indicates dishonest users.variability. The same is true for p2: now the projection is onto the direction of next-largest-variability.Our strategy to achieve consensus is as follows. The cumulative fraction of variance (αk) explained by the kth component is given by [18]: ki=1 λiαk =  E λ . (A5)j=1 jSetting a fixed variance threshold (α) allows us to extract the number of components (n) needed to explain at least α×100% of the report matrix’s total variance. The coor- dination vector c is calculated by summing together the (centered) data projections onto the first n components, weighted by their eigenvalues:nc = X λjsj. (A6)j=1Element ci of the coordination vector is an estimate of the non-conformity of user i. A high score indicates that this user contributed a great deal to the system’s overall variability – that is, the user often disagreed with the consensus – and therefore was likely not honest. The user is therefore punished (Fig. 6).The remainder of our consensus calculation, and Repu- tation redistribution calculation, is identical to the spec- ification of [3].Appendix B: Smart ContractsA decentralized prediction market can be constructed in a relatively straightforward way using smart contracts, such as Ethereum [20, 21]. Due to the recent release of12            −3 x 1010.50−0.5−1−1.5−2−2.5 12345678non−conformity                                                                                 Appendix A: Consensus Algorithm  change in reputation
Serpent contracts on Counterparty, we are also testing an alternative implementation of Augur using Serpent. Counterparty’s announcement frees us to use Bitcoin as the transactional currency on our platform, instead of having to use Ethereum’s ether – this will also be reme- died on Ethereum itself when sidechains are released.We think smart contracts may provide an alternative method for implementing Augur. However, there are sev- eral potential barriers related to security and scalability. We are currently testing our contract implementation and will update the whitepaper with our results.Appendix C: LMSR DerivationHere we present a simple derivation of the logarith- mic market scoring rule (LMSR), using the principle of Maximum Entropy [22–24].Let qi denote the number of shares outstanding of out- come i, and P (qi) denote the probability that there are qi outstanding shares of outcome i. The entropy of the market is given by the standard form [14, 25]:S({qi})=− P(qi)logP(qi), (C1) iwhere the sum is over all possible outcomes in this mar- ket. Suppose there are two constraints on the entropy. The first is the mean number of shares outstanding, across all outcomes in the market,hold for all possible i, it simplifies to: logP(qi)+1+α+βqi =0. (C5)Using Eq. C3 to eliminate the normalization parameter e−1−α, reveals the Boltzmann distribution:e−βqi P(qi)=  e−βqjj−1 −βqi=Z e , (C6)13  ⟨q⟩ =   qiP (qi) , iand the second is normalization:(C2)where Z is the canonical partition function:Z =   e−βqi . (C7)iAs in statistical physics, Eq. C6 describes a family of probability distributions, characterized by the value of the Lagrange multiplier β. The value of β, which is set by data, is the connection between the information-theoretic derivation and reality. In thermodynamics, β is the in- verse of the system’s temperature; for a market, it is set by the market’s liquidity. Examining Eq. C6 and Eq. 4, it is clear that β is set by the LMSR’s loss limit parameter (l),1β=−l, (C8)we see that Eq. C6 is identical to the LMSR price function (Eq. 4):p(qi) = P(qi) = Z−1 eqi/l. (C9) Eq. C9 is the result expected for a prediction market: theprice offered for shares of outcome i is exactly equal to the probability that outcome i will occur.In this framing, the number of shares qi is analogous to a thermodynamic energy (or internal energy). The LMSR’s cost function is just the logarithm of the sum of statistical weights, which we have identified as the sys- tem’s partition function (Eq. C7).C({qi})=−llogZ =⟨q⟩+lS. (C10)This is identical to the Helmholtz free energy, a thermo- dynamic function which describes the amount of work re- quired to generate the system’s observed statistical con- figuration. This configuration is the distribution of en- ergy levels for a thermodynamic system; for a market governed by the LMSR, it is the share distribution. iThe market’s Lagrangian is Λ ({qi}) = S − ⟨q⟩ − 1. The constrained maximum entropy is found where the derivative of Λ vanishes,dΛ= dP(q) logP(q)+1+α+βq =0, (C4) iiiiwhere the multipliers α and β enforce normalization and constraint C2, respectively. Since Eq. C4 is required toP(qi)=1. (C3)
