Decibel.LIVE: A Decentralized Noise Pollution Monitoring and Incentive Platform ∗ABSTRACTNoise pollution is one of the leading causes which adversely affect the well-being and quality of life of residents in urban areas. In this paper we present Decibel.LIVE, a blockchain based decentralized platform to monitor urban noise and compensate residents living around the noise sites. With the Decibel.LIVE smartphone app, citizens can measure their personal exposure to noise using smartphones as noise sen- sors and report excess noise to business owners responsible for the noise sites over private encrypted channels. The platform also implements a settlements infrastructure based on blockchain technology which enables business owners to compensate residents affected by noise in real-time. The platform aggregates noise levels in a given region and presents visual noise propagation models which can be used by com- munities and local noise enforcement officers to enforce noise guidelines.1. INTRODUCTIONNoise is often described as unwanted sound which is un- pleasant and disruptive to hearing. It affects quality of life because it interferes with activities like sleep, relaxation, conversation or listening to music, TV, radio or natural sounds.In recent decades, increases in population have also led to increases in traffic, construction, demolition and other noise Noise pollution is a common problem in urban environments, affecting human behavior, health and even children’s cogni- tive development.Typically, cities and towns have established guidelines on noise levels allowed in residential areas. Local laws and by- laws may restrict general construction and other sources of noise depending on the neighborhood, commercial zones,∗time of day and days of week such as weekends and holi- days. Cities may employ noise abatement inspectors to en- force noise guidelines. However, proving noise variance when code violations occur isn’t easy with existing methods. Frus- trated residents end up calling local bylaw enforcement or noise control officers. However, without any proof of code violation there’s not much a noise control officer can do.There is both objective and subjective evidence for the evidence of non-auditory effects of noise on health and well- being which are caused by exposure to noise [13]. Exposure to levels above 40 dB(A) begins to influence well being and levels above 60 dB(A) are considered detrimental to health. There is good evidence, largely from laboratory studies, that noise exposure impairs performance [8]. Noise exposure dur- ing sleep may increase blood pressure, heart rate and finger pulse amplitude as well as body movements. There may also be after-effects during the day following disturbed sleep; perceived sleep quality, mood and performance in terms of reaction time are all decreased following sleep disturbed by noise [14].In this paper we present Decibel.LIVE, a novel approach to noise pollution monitoring using blockchain technology and smartphones. Leveraging the decentralized nature of the blockchain and the continuous climb in smartphone own- ership and internet usage, we present an open and low-cost platform to monitor noise pollution.https://www.decibel.live Vijay Kandy and Shane Loomb{vijay,shane}@decibel.live March 25, 2017 This is a draft release. A final version will be published when the application is deployed to Ethereum mainnet.This section summarizes noise measurement techniques particularly environment noise. We review noise measure- ment techniques and tools to capture noise data.Sound or noise is the result of pressure variations, or oscil- lations, in an elastic medium (e.g., air, water, solids), gener- ated by a vibrating surface. Sound propagates in the form of longitudinal waves, involving a succession of compressions and rarefactions in the elastic medium [6]. Appendix A gives a glossary of acoustic terminology.As sound waves travel outward from the source, their intensity (loudness) expressed as watts per square meter (W/m2 ) steadily decreases due to several natural phenom- ena such as spreading with distance, absorption by the at- mosphere and wind and temperature changes. In a free field, the intensity and sound pressure at a given point, at a dis- tance r (in meters) from the source, is expressed by [6]:12.NOISE ASSESSMENTLisez Euler, lisez Euler, c’est notre matre tous.— Pierre-Simon Laplace
 hours. Therefore a single dB(A) measurement isnt a very good indicator of noise pollution. A much better indication is a logarithmic average, LAeq,T which is the metric of choice for measuring exposure to noise.LAeq,T is the equivalent continuous dB(A) level which has the same energy as the original fluctuating noise for the same given period of time T and is defined as [12]:1 T pA(t)2 LAeq,T = 10log10 (T p2 00dt) (3)  Figure 1: Attenuation rate at 6dBA per doubling of the distance.p2 = ρcI = ρcW (1) 4πr2where ρ and c are the air density and speed of sound respec- tively.From the preceding equation, if the sound pressure level, Lm, is measured at some reference distance, rm, from the noise source then the sound pressure level at some other distance, r, may be estimated using [1]:Lp = Lm − 20log10 ( r ) (2) rmIt follows that in free field conditions, the noise level de- creases by 6 dB each time the distance between the source and the observer doubles (See Figure 1).However, free-field conditions don’t exist in urban envi- ronments so, in general the equation relating sound pressure level and sound power level is modified to account for the presence of reflecting surfaces.In the near field where distance from the source is equal to about a wavelength of sound or equal to three times the largest dimension of the sound source (whichever is the larger), the sound field does not decrease by 6 dB each time the distance from the source is increased (as it does in the far field).Our focus is the far field of a source which begins where the near field ends and extends to infinity. This is the field where the citizens affected by noise pollution reside. Note that the transition from near to far field is gradual in the transition region. In the far field, the direct field radiated by most machinery sources will decay at the rate of 6 dB each time the distance from the source is doubled. For line sources such as traffic noise, the decay rate varies between 3 dB and 4 dB [6].2.1 Measuring environmental noise dB(A)The basic unit of measurement for environmental noise, as recommended by ISO 1996/1, is the dB(A). Noise emission limits are also usually expressed in dB(A). Noise levels may be measured at any moment, but noise levels vary widely with time, e.g., traffic noise is higher at noon than at mid- night and higher still during the morning and evening rushwhere pA(t) is obtained from applying A-weighting filter to the raw acoustic signal p(t) and p0 is a standard ref- erence value corresponding to the minimal audible acoustic signal (20μP a in air). The raw acoustic signal p(t) is filtered (A-weighting) to compute the relative loudness of sound as perceived by the human ear. A weighting is (formally de- fined standards IEC 61672-1 and ANSI 1.43) in the analog or frequency domain and converted to a time domain digital filter, normally done with z-transform or bilinear transform.Zero dB(A) is considered the point at which a person be- gins to hear sound[3]. A soft whisper at 1 meter measures at 30 dB(A), a busy freeway at 15 meters at around 80 dB(A), and a chain saw can reach 110 dB(A) or more at operating distance. Brief exposure to noise levels exceeding 120 dB(A) without hearing protection may even cause physical pain.Decibel.LIVE smartphone app implements filtering to pro- duce dB(A) events.2.2 Techniques for capturing noise levelsTechniques to monitor noise in urban areas vary based on jurisdictions. Typically, noise measurements in urban areas are carried out by designated officers or consultants who collect data at a particular location using a sound level meter or similar microphone-equipped device. However, the measuring sessions take place only at few accessible spots and during short time intervals (e.g., 30 minutes).There are a number of limitations with such approaches. Noise mapping campaigns are expensive due to need of ex- pertise and human resources, the deployment of sound level meter devices and the processing effort. Also, data collec- tion at sparse locations and at specific times often produce computational models with an unknown error margins.2.2.1 Alternative ApproachesOver the last few years, smartphone adoption has been rising worldwide[10]. Modern smartphones have significant computational power, always-on internet connectivity and built-in sensors such as microphones, cameras, global posi- tioning system (GPS) receiver, accelerometers, gyroscopes, and proximity and light sensors making them as sensors carried by humans rather than placed at static locations. Smartphone developers now offer many sound measurement applications that are accurate and reliable to be used to as- sess occupational noise exposures[7]. This has given rise to a low-cost alternative to traditional large-scale, costly and difficult to manage sensing infrastructure based on sensor networks.One such novel implementation is NoiseTube[9] which is a mobile application platform that monitors noise pollution involving the general public. Citizens measure their personal exposure to noise in their everyday environment by using GPS-equipped mobile phones as noise sensors. VANET[11]  2
takes a different approach by using a mesh network com- posed of mobile phones for detecting noise and transporting noise data. These projects show that smartphones can be used effectively as noise sensors to monitor noise pollution.seconds on average, the Ethereum transaction rate is slower than that of a typical centralized database.Also, storing every transaction in a smart contract can be expensive due to the gas price.State channels are a promising approach[2] addressing the scaling problem by moving some of the transactions off chain, while preserving the systems decentralized structure and strong integrity guarantees.Instead of submitting every transaction to the blockchain, state channels employ the blockchain to first establish a shared deposit between two parties. The parties interact directly and communicate with the blockchain only to close channels or to resolve disputes between the parties. There- fore state channels dramatically increase the transaction rate while preserving all the benefits of the blockchain.A state channel χP1→P2 between two parties P1 and P2 is created on chain using a hashed time locked contract CPreimage which acts as an escrow. A channel is initial- ized when party P1 creates a conditional commitment (a micropayment or a bid etc.) by sending a hash h to preim- age contract CP reimage such that h = H(σ) is the hash of a secret string σ only known to party P1. The channel is valid until time TExpiry.The state of the channel is concluded in one of three ways:1) When party P1 closes the channel by sending a finalcommitment and publishing the preimage σ to CP reimage.2) When party P2 closes the channel by publishing the latestcommitment it received to CP reimage.3) Or in case of a dispute when one or both parties are not in agreement of the latest state of the commitment. Typically parties establish dispute resolution policies and may employ a arbiter contract.We denote a state channel between two parties P1 and P2asP1 −−−−−−−−−−−−−−→ P2 (4) CPreimage[h,TExpiry]where party P1 makes a commitment to party P2 an action denoted by commitment (a micropayment or a bid etc.) by publishing the preimage σ of hash h = H(σ) before time TExpiry.3.ETHEREUM BLOCKCHAINTCP implementations will follow a general principle of robustness: be conservative in what you do, be liberal in what you accept from others.— Jon Postel, RFC: 793, Transmission Control ProtocolIn the strictest sense, a blockchain 1 is a type of database that is shared across nodes geographically distributed in a network. No single entity owns the data on a blockchain and the design of a blockchain makes it infeasible to modify data once it’s published on a public blockchain like Ethereum.We have chosen Ethereum blockchain as the platform for Decibel.LIVE service.3.1 Why Ethereum?For Decibel.LIVE, the primary use of blockchain is as a shared public database. We want any user of Decibel.LIVE to be able to submit a transaction to the blockchain. The transaction propagates throughout the network and is even- tually committed into a consistent ordered ledger.Any party can view all the transactions committed on the blockchain. If any party’s view includes a transaction tx, then every party’s view will also include tx after a maximum time bound. Therefore we need a time bound, ∆, which bounds the maximum delay round trip time for a blockchain transaction such that if a party P1 submits a transaction tx at time T, then all parties have the same view of confirmed transaction tx within time T + ∆.Our choice of Ethereum as blockchain platform is due to the following:1) Ethereum [15] is one of the biggest public blockchains with over 6,000 full nodes running as of this writing [5].2) Blocks are confirmed in a few seconds, typically around 15-17 seconds 2.3) Ethereum also provides a Turing-complete language called Solidity which is used to write smart contracts.Smart contracts are programs which consist of data decla-rations and high-level functions. Users interact with a smart contract by publishing a transaction containing a procedure call, including the address of the contract, the name of the function to invoke, and arguments to pass.A user submits a transaction tx by paying a gas fee. The gas price is the cost of executing the smart contract code on Ethereum blockchain.3.2 State ChannelsWhile blockchains as distributed ledgers have proven to be successful at low transaction volumes, scalability is a con- cern. As blocks are added to Ethereum blockchain every 121The terms blockchain and distributed ledger are often treated as synonyms in the industry even though blockchain is a specific type of distributed ledger2 https://blog.ethereum.org/2015/09/14/on-slow-and-fast- block-times/commitment4.DECIBEL.LIVE ARCHITECTUREI often say that when you can measure what you are speaking about, and express it in numbers, you know something about it; but when you cannot measure it, when you cannot express it in numbers, your knowledge is of a meagre and unsatisfactory kind; it may be the beginning of knowledge, but you have scarcely, in your thoughts, advanced to the stage of science, whatever the matter may be.— Lord Kelvin, Electrical Units of MeasurementDecibel.LIVE is a synthesis of ideas presented in the pre- vious two sections. The platform consists of two distinct components:1) Smartphone app to capture noise levels and store com- pensation transactions with the built-in wallet.2) DApp (short for decentralized application) consists of: 3
 Table 1: Noise Collection Fields  Field  Type Description beneficiaryId  string represents a resident lat  decimal latitude long  decimal longitude db  integer db(A) level timestamp  integer UNIX timestamp      a) a smart contract CDecibelLive. 3b) Bel (ß), an ERC20 token built on top of Ethereum.c) an API to interact with the smart contract on the blockchain.d) a mesh routing network to link and manage secure off-chain channels.4.1 Smartphone appThe Decibel.LIVE app is available for free and can be in- stalled on GPS equipped smartphones. A beneficiary uses Decibel.LIVE app to monitor noise and send noise events in JSON format to the initiator over the secure Telehash channel.4.1.1 Gathering Noise DataThe Decibel.LIVE app collects five fields as shown in ta- ble 1 including beneficiaryId representing a beneficiary, geolocation (lat, long) where noise sample was captured, the noise level in dB(A) (db), and the time when the noise was captured (timestamp). No additional information is cap- tured.The app measures the loudness level of the captured en- vironmental sound at 22500 Hz, 16 bits/second at a cho- sen interval. The app contains a real-time signal processing module which applies infinite impulse response (IIR) and computes LAeq,T in dB(A) as the primary indicator of noise pollution. IIR filters are used as they tend to mimic the performance of traditional analog filters and make use of feedback.The app also takes into account two common noise indica- tors, Lnight and Lden which represent the equivalent sound levels averaged over the night only (to assess sleep distur- bance) and over the whole day, respectively.These values on the A-weighted dB scale are used in the payout settlement algorithm (see Algorithm 1).4.1.2 Storing Noise DataNoise events collected on all secure channels are stored in a local database and persisted on IPFS4 periodically. Events are organized by noise contract and beneficiary:/DecibelLIVE/{:deedId}/events/{:beneficiaryId}At any time, payout settlement can be verified using the noise events and policies in any noise contract CNoise even after the contract becomes inactive.4.2 The DApp3Currently the contract is deployed on Ropsten Testnet at: 0XBD29DD4534F2DD0A8B5F4AA366A02451795FF09D4 https://ipfs.io/Figure 2: Mesh network of secure channels connect- ing initiator, beneficiaries, and Preimage contract.The dApp consists of a smart contract which we denote here as CDecibelLive and a web based API5 to provide read and write access to the contract.There are four types of identities in the Decibel.LIVE platform that interact with CDecibelLive contract – Initiator, Beneficiary, Noise Smart Contract and Contract Monitor.4.2.1 InitiatorAn initiator is an individual or business responsible for the noise site. Every initiator is assigned a wallet within the Decibel.LIVE platform. The wallet consists of a secret-key sk, a public-key pk derived from the secret key, and unique Ethereum address ainitiator = (pk, sk) constructed from the public-key.An initiator creates a smart contract for monitoring noise at a noise site.4.2.2 Beneficiary5The live site is at https://www.decibel.live and con- nects to Ethereum Mainnet. The test site is at https://test.decibel.live and connects to Ethereum Testnet  4
A beneficiary is any party (i.e., residents, other busi- nesses) affected by noise originating from initiator’s noise site. Every beneficiary is also assigned a wallet consisting a secret-key sk′, a public-key pk′ derived from the secret key, and unique Ethereum address abeneficiary = (pk′,sk′) constructed from the public-key.4.2.3 Noise Smart ContractCDecibelLive creates and deploys new noise smart contractson behalf of initiators. A noise contract which we denote asCNoise encapsulates information about the noise site such asthe location (latitude and longitude coordinates), Ethereumaddresses of N beneficiaries abenef iciary ...abenef iciary con- 1Nfirmed by Decibel.LIVE as residents living within an area of radius r meters from the noise site. Following are the attributes of a noise contract.    // Reference to Decibel.LIVE system    address decibel;    // Defines a location reference. Location    // coordinates are stored multiplying by    // 10^6 (i.e., coordinates have 6 digits    // after the decimal point)    int32 lat;    int32 long;    // contract valid from (Unix timestamp)    uint8 beginsAt;    // contract valid till (Unix timestamp)    uint8 endsAt;    // Refers to the initiator    InitiatingParty initiatingParty;    // contract id    bytes32 deedId;    // A dictionary of beneficiaries with    // beneficiaryIds as keys    mapping (bytes32 => BeneficiaryParty)      public beneficiaryParties;    // Store keys separately    bytes32[] beneficiaryIds;    // Current state of the contract    State public state;    // payout policies per currency and base unit    // set in the deed    PayoutPolicy[] payoutPolicies;An initiator creates a noise contract by filling out a con- tract template from the web or mobile application. The plat- form uses an implementation of smart contract templates[4] to create and deploy noise contracts. In essence, CDecibelLive uses a creational pattern and acts as a factory to create new instances of CNoise on behalf of an initiator. Following method in CDecibelLive creates a new noise contract.    function newDeed(        bytes32 _deedId,Table 2: Example payout policies    address _initiatingParty,    Holding.Currency _currency,    uint256 _initialBalance,    int32 _lat,int32 _long )    public    onlyDecibel    returns(address){    Deed deed = new Deed(_deedId, _initiatingParty,    _currency, _initialBalance, _lat, _long);   Day DuringThreshold dB(A)  Payout  Sat 6AM - 5PM60 - 70  ß1/min  Sun 6AM - 5PM60 - 70  ß1.50/min  Sun 7PM - 11PM60 - 70  ß5/min    5     deeds[_deedId] = deed;    deedIds.length++;    deedIds[deedIds.length - 1] = _deedId;    return (deed);}The modifier onlyDecibel ensures that new noise con- tracts can be created through CDecibelLive only by the Deci- bel.LIVE platform.4.2.4 Contract MonitorA monitor is a local authority that wishes to monitor noise at a particular site in real time. A monitor is also assigned a wallet consisting of a key pair and unique Ethereum ad- dress amonitor = (pk′′, sk′′) constructed from the public-key. However, a monitor is a read-only observer in the system.4.2.5 Bel token (ß)The DApp platform uses Bel token (ß), an ERC20-compliant token built on top of Ethereum, as the unit of compensation on the blockchain-based platform. Within Decibel.LIVE, initiators define compensation policies using Bel tokens.A beneficiary receives compensation in the form of Bel tokens. Bels can exchanged on a crypto currency exchange or can be reused on the platform.The distribution of Bels and the token supply is deter- mined by a smart contract deployed on Ethereum.4.2.6 Payout PoliciesAn initiator also declares incentives in the form of com- pensation when noise exceeds a certain threshold at certain times during the day (or night) by hour(s) of day and day(s) of week. Such payout policies are encapsulated in CNoise by an initiator when a noise contract is created (see Table 2). When the contract becomes active, the policies can not be changed.The payout settlement algorithm (see Algorithm 1) evalu- ates every incoming noise event as per the payment policies in a noise contract.4.2.7 Noise Contract ExpirationA noise contract expires when endsAt block.timestamp. block is a built-in Solidity property and block.timestamp
gives the Unix timestamp of the latest block. Following method in CNoise expires a noise contract 6.    function expire()        onlyDecibel        inState(State.Active)    {        if(endsAt >= block.timestamp) {            expired();            state = State.Inactive;} }4.2.8 Noise Contract CancellationAn initiator can abort a noise contract before it be- comes active. Both web and mobile applications provide means to abort a noise contract if it’s not yet in Active state. The modifier inState(State.Created) ensures such guarantees.    function abort()        onlyDecibel        inState(State.Created)    {aborted();        state = State.Inactive;    }4.2.9 State ChannelDecibel.LIVE uses Telehash7, an encrypted mesh network protocol for communication between the initiator and each beneficiary. Telehash enables a completely distributed, decentralized communication mechanism that doesn’t rely on on centralized or federated servers.When a noise contract CNoise becomes active, the initiator and every beneficiary of the contract is assigned a unique Telehash address known as a hashname. A hashname is a 32-byte string that corresponds to the SHA-256 hash of one or more public keys. A link or a channel is created connect- ing the initiator to every beneficiary of the contract. All messages exchanged on a channel are encrypted end-to-end all of the time using forward secrecy.CP reimage creates a new channel on behalf of an initiator with an opening balance of ßb and hash h = H(σ) where σ is secret chosen by the initiator. ßb is the maximum amount the initiator is willing to pay while the contract is active. The beneficiary joins the channel after confirming the owner of the channel using ecrecover function in Solidity.address initiatorPK = ecrecover(h, r, s, v)where r, s, v represents the signature of initiator’s trans-in JSON format over this channel to the initiator. Each noise event from a beneficiary is evaluated and if eligi- ble, a payout commitment is sent from the initiator. The beneficiary’s balance in the wallet is updated in real time.A monitor may observe noise events events originating from a site in real time by establishing a channel to the initiator.a0CP [h′,TExpiry]ßb initiator −−−−−−−−−→ a1CP [h′′,TExpiry] where CP is the preimage contract.monitorßc benef iciary −−−−−−−−−−→ a24.2.10 Compensation SettlementThe LAeq,T events are input into the payout settlement algorithm (Algorithm 1). Each incoming event is checked against the payout policies declared in the associated noise contract. If an LAeq,T event is eligible for compensation, the beneficiary’s balance is updated on the channel in real- time.When the contract expires, the balances on the channel are published on CDecibelLive permanently recording transfer of funds.Algorithm 1 Payout Settlement(6)  action.The degree to which data is accurate and reliable is the biggest challenge of the application. To that end, Deci- bel.LIVE aims to ensure high accuracy of sensor data and low probability of incorrect inputs from a dishonest actor.4.3.1 Dishonest Actors and Gaming the SystemThere are a few ways in which dishonest actors might try to game the system for their own financial benefit.a) Joining the contract as beneficiaries when they don’t reside within the contract zone It is feasible that individuals might try to temporarily position them- selves within the approved contract zone for the purpose of joining and thus benefiting from the contract. The incentives for doing this are minimal given that the in- dividual(s) would need to be present within the contract zone for a reasonable amount of time to benefit in any substantive way. However, this possibility does need to be considered and will be mitigated through authentica- tion i.e. pre-issuing a unique passcode to each nearby resident which must be entered to join the contract.initiatorßb benef iciary −−−−−−−−−−−−−−→ a2(5) The Decibel.LIVE app captures loudness of noise on a6Currently the Decibel.LIVE platform invokes expire() method using a scheduled job. In future versions, we plan on using an Oracle service to execute methods at a scheduled future time.7 https://github.com/telehasha1beneficiary’s smartphone, computes and sends LAeq,T eventsCPreimage[h,TExpiry]1: 2: 3: 4: 5: 6: 7: 8: 9:10: 11: 12: 13:4.3[C1...Cn] ← GetNoiseContracts(CDecibelLive) fori←1tondowhile Ci is active doPolicySeti ←GetPolicies(Ci) Evaluate f(PolicySeti)for all noise events ε in ξ doif f(ε,PolicySeti) is payable thenpayouti ←Eligible(ε,PolicySeti) TransferFunds(CDecibelLive, Ci, payouti)end if end forend while end forVeracity of Data  6
b) Artificially distorting noise readings to increase payouts Individuals might try to increase the noise read- ings through a variety of techniques like pre-recording the noise closer to the sound source and playing it back, generating another noise source within their residence, blowing into the microphone on their smartphone to in- crease the sound pressure etc. These techniques will be mitigated through sophisticated analysis of sound snip- pets (short duration audio recordings of < 1sec taken at periodic intervals) for those noise readings that are iden- tified as statistical outliers. Options such as banning the user for the duration of the contract or a fixed period of time (e.g. 30 days) may also be considered. It is even- tually planned that much of this process will automated using AI.c) Joining the noise contract multiple times This will be resolved by allowing each resident to join the contract once only using pre-authentication techniques described above. In addition, GPS locations for noise readings will need to correspond to the beneficiaries location essen- tially eliminating the ability for a resident to join/moni- tor the contract on behalf of another nearby resident but all from their within the bounds of their own residence.4.3.2 CalibrationPrior to capturing noise levels, the smartphone app per- forms a set of calibrations. Data from an improperly cali- brated smartphone is misleading and not useful. GPS mod- ules in modern smartphones have a very high positioning accuracy sufficient enough to calculate the distance from a noise site. The app correlates GPS data with known infor- mation to determine the veracity of noise events.5. CONCLUSIONSIn this paper we presented Decibel.LIVE, a noise moni- toring and incentive platform which enables citizens moni- tor noise and report noise events to noise site owners on a private encrypted channel. Site owners can define compen- sation policies based on the loudness of noise. Decibel.LIVE helps citizens receive instant compensation from noise site owners when noise exceeds thresholds defined by site owners.6. ACKNOWLEDGMENTSWe express our gratitude to Dr. Ralph Muehleisen for help with signal processing and IIR filters. Thanks to Steve Anderson for long discussions on many of these ideas and thanks to members of the Ethereum community who have been generous with their knowledge.7. REFERENCES[1] D. A.Bies and C. H.Hansen. Engineering Noise Control: Theory and Practice. Spon Press, 1996.[2] R. K. Andrew Miller, Iddo Bentov and P. McCorry. Sprites: Payment channels that go faster than lightning. February 2017.[3] R. Chepesiuk. Decibel Hell: The Effects of Living in a Noisy World. National Institue of Environmental Health Sciences, January 2005.[4] L. B. Christopher D. Clack, Vikram A. Bakshi. Smart contract templates: foundations, design landscape and research directions. 2016.[5] Ethernodes.org. Ethernodes.org. https://www.ethernodes.org/network/1. Accessed February 25, 2017.[6] P. C. H. Hansen. Fundamentals of acoustics. pages 24–27, 1996.[7] C. A. Kardous and P. B. Shaw. In Evaluation of smartphone sound measurement applications, March 2014.[8] M. Loeb. Noise And Human Efficiency. Chichester: Wiley, 1986.[9] N. Maisonneuve, M. Stevens, M. E. Niessen,P. Hanappe, and L. Steels. In Citizen Noise Pollution Monitoring, 2009.[10] M. Meeker. Kpcb: Internet trends 2016 - code conference. http://www.kpcb.com/internet-trends. Accessed February 25, 2017.[11] D. Radu, C. Avram, and J. Y. Adina Astilean. InAcoustic noise pollution monitoring in an urbanenvironment using a VANET network, May 2012.[12] S. Santini and A. Vitaletti. In First experiences usingwireless sensor networks for noise pollutionmonitoring, April 2008.[13] S. A. Stansfeld and M. P. Matheson. Noise pollution:non-auditory effects on health. Department of Psychiatry, Medical Sciences Building, Queen Mary, University of London, 2013.[14] C. J. e. a. Vallet M, Gagneux J. Heart rate reactivity to aircraft noise after a long-term exposure. in: Rossi g (ed) noise as a public health problem. milan: Centro recherche e studioamplifon. pages 965–75, 1983.[15] G. Wood. Ethereum: A secure decentralised generalised transaction ledger. 2014.7
APPENDIXA. GLOSSARYBlockchain A blockchain is an append-only distributed ledger of transactions. Transactions confirmed and verified by multiple nodes (computers connected forming a blockchain network with the task of validating and relaying transac- tions) are recorded as ”blocks” which are added in a linear, chronological order with each blocking linking its predeces- sor forming a chain from the very first block. Each node gets a copy of the blockchain, which gets downloaded auto- matically upon joining the network.Direct Field A direct field of a sound source is the area of the sound field which has not suffered any reflection from any surfaces or obstacles.Elastic Medium A substance or material (e.g., air , wa- ter) that can change its form as a result of a deforming force but can return to its original form when the deforming force is removed. For example, a gas is an elastic medium as it can be compressed under pressure but will regain its former volume when the pressure is released.ERC20 Token A de facto token standard to create digi-tal assets one can purchase and own on the Ethereum blockchain. The standard defines a set of function signatures such as send, register, delete, in the Ethereum contract ABI lan- guage. Using the ERC20 token standards, crypto currency exchanges, users and applications easily interact with each other exchanging currency units, registering names, making offers on exchanges, and other similar functions.Free Field Free field is a region in space where sound may propagate free from any form of obstruction.Frequency Analysis Frequency analysis is a process by which a time varying signal in the time domain is trans- formed to its frequency components in the frequency do- main. There are two ways of transforming a signal from the time domain to the frequency domain. The first involvesthe use of band limited digital or analog filters. The second involves the use of Fourier analysis where the time domain signal is transformed using a Fourier series. This is imple- mented in practice digitally (referred to as the DFT - digital Fourier Transform) using a very efficient algorithm known as the FFT (Fast Fourier Transform).Hash function A hash function is a mathematical func- tion that takes an input of any size and produces an output of fixed size.Impulse A signal can be decomposed into a group of simple additive components called impulses. Generally, an impulse is a short-duration time-domain signal. A unit im- pulse is a normalized impulse where sample number zero has a value of one, while all other samples have a value of zero. A unit impulse is also known as a delta function and is de- noted by δ(t) for continuous systems and δ[n] for discrete systems.Impulse Response Impulse response is the output signal of a system when a delta function (unit impulse) is applied as the input.Hashlock Hashlock is a type of restriction placed on a transaction such that a user must provide the input string used to produce the hash which is part of the transaction.Oracle Oracles are special smart contracts that connect a contract on the blockchain with outside datasources.Signals and Systems In digital signal processing, a sig- nal is a description of how one parameter varies with an- other parameter. For e.g., voltage changing over time in an electronic circuit, or brightness varying with distance in an image. A system is any process that produces an output signal in response to an input signal. A system is called continuous if its input and output are continuous signals. For e.g., a voltage depending on time: v(t). A system is discrete if its input and output are discrete signals. For e.g., a stock price measured by day: p[d].Transaction A message from a user to be recorded on the blockchain.8