  INVESTFEED INC FEED TOKEN PRE-SALE PLANThe first to market and leading cryptocurrency social investment network. We invite you to participate in our token pre-sale and ICO. Find the details inside on how you can become a key member in our community or visit us at www.investFeed.com  Welcome to web 3.0: An Incentivized Next-Generation Social Investment Network for Cryptocurrencies0 
  2. THE PROBLEM     1  No central hub to buy/sell/exchange, access market data and news, or to chat about existing and emerging cryptocurrencies    2  No dedicated network for enthusiasts and professionals globally in the blockchain industry    Cryptocurrencies, especially newer alt coins, suffer from lack of exposure, and in turn generate little value for those who are not actively using a network 3    4Content creators recognize how advertising may diminish their works value to the consumer     Crypto and alt coins information is too fragmented and scattered. Centralization is needed 5    Revenue opportunties for active community contributors are weak 6  3
3. THE SOLUTIONWe have built a smarter social networking and market access platform (Browser and Mobile) for the cryptocurrency community. This will enable the community to establish professional relationships, learn, manage their wallets, and exchange ideas.A smarter social networking and market access platform for the cryptocurrency community.The investFeed platform will:▪ Ensure every cryptocurrency has its own dedicated feed, market data, and blockchain history.▪ Allow users to earn & exchange digital currency, cryptocurrency, and money.▪ Provide multi-language support to accommodate global consumption.▪ Encourageuserstoshareandboostcontentforviralsearchtobringvaluetomanypassive users. Creators posting to investFeed may monetize merely by having theirwork recognized (or “liked”) by the investFeed community.▪ Create clarity for the rapidly growing dynamic crypto and alt coin space.▪ Accurately and transparently reward an unbounded number of individuals whomake subjective contributions to the community.▪ Allow users to establish career profiles on the social network▪ Empower users to skip credit cards altogether and process FEED Token paymentsfrom smartphone to smartphone.     4
4. INVESTFEED GOALSinvestFeed plans to disrupt the cryptocurrency industry by bringing transparency and ease of use which are currently lacking. Our main goal is to integrate cryptocurrencies into the traditional financial world and to create a single gateway to the market that is open, transparent, and rewards-based for all our users, contributors, and financial institutions wherever they may be in the world.We have been in operation since 2014 and have a fully built-out social investing platform with multiple social networking features. This is not a planned product. It exists today. Our investFeed Social network app for Android and iOS is available in the respective app stores. We have experience and a proven track record maintaining a platform that caters to the needs of our users.Our existing platform has over 15 thousand member sign-ups with over 200 thousand live feeds since launch. 78% of our users are experienced traders, 54% are affluent US adults ($100k+) and 52% are self-employed or founders. This user base can be seamlessly converted to our crypto-offering. Again, these are not forecasted user numbers. They exist today. Additionally, most crypto-traders invest in traditional financial assets as well as cryptocurrencies and so there is a natural synergy between our existing and new offering.We are building a new financial ecosystem, a new way and we want our community to be our token holders. As much as we believe in the democratization of digital transacting, we also believe in putting the power of our community back into the hands of the community. As such, we are going for an ICO Initial Coin Offering and ask you, the crypto- community to be our supporters.  5
4.1. Goals1. Provide cryptocurrency market data and news as well as fundamental, history, streaming data, charting and technical analysis tools.2. Create cryptocurrency streams for sharing ideas between traders, entrepreneurs, and crypto enthusiasts.3. Provide direct market access to Buy/Sell/Exchange over 721 cryptocurrencies from 3,846 markets, presently.4. Allow for an integrated multi- currency wallet offering.5. Enable the monetization of users’ feeds by allowing the crowd to subscribe to premium contentrelated to cryptocurrency - and allow users to syndicate their content to Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn.6. Create Boost; a unique feature that will allow a content creator to expand their reach by boosting to new networks. Creators can earn points which they can exchange for views. Or users can buy points to level-up your network.7. Gamify the platform with FEED Tokens to incentivize content- creators for their high-quality content.8. Support English, Chinese, Russian, and many other languages.    66
5. INVESTFEED FEATURESinvestFeed is currently a cross-platform social trading platform in production for US Equities, available on Browser, Native iOS, and Native Android.We aim to transform the existing platform and expand on it, to create a "One Tab" solution and dedicated next-generation hub for the entire blockchain and cryptocurrency industry. investFeed will be the epicenter for cryptocurrency social, market data, crowd sentiment, breaking news, information on existing/trending/new projects, as well as have integrated asset portfolio/order management and sharing capabilities.This will be delivered to you via the cryptocurrency epicenter which will feature a range of add-on services to improve your experience. All investFeed services are built on the Ethereum MainNet - to meet the highest level of security and transparency.5.1. Intended User Base       Professional & retail crypto-traders & investors  Newcomers joining to learn & get startedInstitutional funds & managers      Independent and mainstream news outlets who will establish a presence on our networkExisting projects to establish a presence on our networkStartup projects to gain exposure on our network 7
5.2. Primary Platform FeaturesSocial NetworkingCapabilities for industry professionals, media entities, traders, enthusiasts, newcomers, and blockchain companies▪ Member profiles with optional advanced fields for strategy and trader performance, networking, career profiles, company profile, and more▪ Cross platform real-time member to member direct messaging▪ Ability to post and apply to blockchain industry related careers▪ Commenting, liking, sharing, member generated content  8
Live Streaming Feeds and ChannelsLive streaming of feeds and channels for all current and upcoming cryptocurrencies and projects based on currency ticker or project name. Members can interact with these feeds in the following ways:▪ Share 500 character posts into the stream▪ Publish and share full articles with embedded multimedia into the stream▪ Upload and share audio/video multimedia into the stream▪ Share portfolio holdings, performance, and trade activity into the stream. Thedepth of this information can be set by the contributorFundamental Cryptocurrency Market Data▪ Charts▪ Streaming weighted average price▪ Multiple exchange prices and volumes ▪ Fundamental data  9
Trending Assets and Watchlist Signals▪ See what's trending with project and cryptocurrency sentiment indicators, heatmaps, and trending alerts based on crowd sentiment and order activity▪ Import your cryptocurrency portfolio and/or create a watchlist▪ Up to the minute blockchain and cryptocurrency industry and project news,announcements, and analysis▪ Streams for new projects, including analysis from investFeed internal teamWallet and Exchange Integration▪ investFeed will enable members to place trades directly on the platform using their existing cryptocurrency accounts Ethereum, Bitcoin, exchanges, wallets, etc via 3rd party integrations▪ Multiple account portfolio aggregation  10
Advanced Trader Tools▪ Technical analysis cryptocurrency screener tool▪ Advanced portfolio analysis and robo-advisory algorithms▪ Back-testing tools for data analysis and quantitative trading strategies  11
   6. INVESTFEED TOKENEthereum enables the creation of ERC20 tokens, which can be used in an incentive system to replace intermediaries. In investFeed’s system, FEED Tokens will play a key role in providing economic incentives so that the rational behavior of individuals results in common good. Unlike in Twitter where volunteers must donate their time to contribute and validate information, on investFeed’s platform, contributors will be rewarded for their work and incentivized to continue increasing the value of the community ecosystem.6.1. The Role of FEED Token     Incentives  •Give and receive incentives for greatcontent Purchases •Purchase premium content from other members - articles,videos & other•Purchase an ad-free experience across theplatform Boost •Promote aka "Boost" your content by postinga sponsored link or video to attract paying customers     12
6.2. FEED Marketplace CapabilitiesEvery feature in the investFeed platform that gives any added value to its user will require payment using FEED Tokens. Every user who facilitates the use of a feature which in turn gives added value, will be entitled to receive FEED Token.As the network grows, there will be limited token supply versus demand and the value of the FEED Token will naturally appreciate, establishing a healthy ecosystem and control mechanism that rewards beneficial content and suppresses the noise.The below are a list of planned initial use cases for the FEED Token. However, this list is not exhaustive and as we have done in the past, we will listen and respond to our contributors and community network, incorporating their views on how to improve and add more value to the platform and the community.▪ Members (media outlets, professionals and non-professionals equally) can contribute premium content and charge in FEED Token for access▪ Promote your own content and profile for network exposure using FEED Token▪ Experienced investors and analysts can monetize their knowledge and expertise by sharing their ideas, articles, videos, and even portfolio performance and trade activity with their subscribers. The FEED Token fee be will determined by the content provider and may be set on a time-based subscription level or unlockingan individual piece of content▪ Users can follow top traders and analysts and news outlets and receive real timealerts from those members via in platform notifications, email, SMS, and mobilepush notifications using FEED Tokens▪ FEED Tokens will be required to access the higher levels of advanced trader tools▪ FEED Tokens can be used to purchase an ad-free experience from the network 13
6.3. Token TechnologyOur tokens will be of a standardized ERC20 form, so they can easily be integrated or displayable for any other party who wishes to do so. All of this code will be publicly available in our repositories and can be audited by anyone who wishes to do so.6.4. FEED Token Transaction MechanicsThanks to the Ethereum Blockchain all FEED Token payment transfers are performed in a decentralized, autonomous and completely transparent manner. Sites like https://etherscan.io allow you to see and follow transactions on the Ethereum blockchain.We will strive to keep the architectural design and documentation as up to date as possible, so everyone can quickly grasp the underlying investFeed architecture. Currently we are developing a plan to improve and expand our specific technology stack and the full details about the backend solution will be elaborated upon in due course.The initial marketplace mechanics will be centralized as we require a database where we can link contracts to premium content and investFeed products like ad-disabling. Our end goal however, is to fully decentralize the investFeed organization and underlying database by Q1 2019.A connection with the Ethereum MainNet will be handled using Parity, which will serve as our Ethereum node. This will ensure that our connection to the network is always synchronized, and transactions can be processed and validated quickly and securely. A React and Web3 stack will be used as our front-end bridge and interface to monitor all events in real-time and record them in the database. 14
     7. CORE TEAM Ronald Chernesky Chief Executive OfficerRon is the driving force behind the strategy, vision and organic growth of investFeed. He co- founded multiple disruptive fintech startups with thousands of followers. He started in New York City as a floor trader and turned a brokerage firm into a global operation opening multiple offices and onboarding over 250+ candidates. Ron is a self- made entrepreneur and is also an aspiring musician, designer, and developer.Andrew Freedman Chief Technology OfficerDrew is the architect and technical lead of the investFeed community. Prior, Drew began his professional career as a full stack web developer and brings over 10 years of experience in technology. Drew has built custom solutions for numerous financial services firms, with a focus on critical risk and reporting applications, including at World Trade Financial Group where he oversaw the development of an enterprise social network and risk management system that was used by the firm globally. In his spare time, Drew enjoys flat faced cats, cooking, and philosophical debates.    15
     Justin Jovanovic Chief Operations OfficerJustin is a master strategist and plays a pivotal role executing the direction of the investFeed community. He focuses on partnerships, data analytics, marketing, community management, and growth of organic culture. Previously, Justin has created and managed a disruptive software development and event sales company and has consulted for numerous NYC-based startups. Justin has a passion for trading and investing, particularly in emerging technology. In his spare time, Justin enjoys fitness, travel, and modern art.Clayton Lambert Full-Stack DeveloperClayton is a full stack developer with skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, jQuery, MySQL, Node.js, C++, and Java. He started web development in early 2012, not only learning how to do back-end development but also later transitioning into front- end developing beautiful user interfaces. In 2006, at the early age of 11, he began learning to program in Visual Basic and C#. Once he started programming, he was hooked, not only to software but to the hardware that he could control with his code. Clayton has also been involved in music, playing in bands and building recording studios for past employers.    16
      7.1. AdvisorsTarryn Valle Financial ConsultantTarryn holds the CFA and FRM designations and a Masters degree in Finance from the University of Cape Town. She is currently a finance lecturer and financial consultant focusing on financial strategy and planning for startups. Previously she worked within the financial services industry, in Cape Town and London, and has participated in a number of finance and investment-based startup ventures. Tarryn is passionate about education and loves supporting projects that empower individuals to make better financial decisions.George Samman Technical AdvisorGeorge is a blockchain and cryptocurrency consultant and advisor to financial institutions, startups and law firms. He is an Entrepreneur in Residence for Blockchain & Cryptocurrency at Tyro Fintech Hub. George also co-founded BTC.sx, now magnr, a bitcoin trading platform in 2013. He is a former Wall Street Senior Portfolio Manager and Market Strategist as well as a technical analyst. George holds the Chartered Market Technician (CMT) designation.   17
     Toshendra Sharma ICO AdvisorTosh is listed in Forbes India 30Under30 List of 2016 in Technology space. Sharma graduated from IIT Bombay (India) is the founder & CEO of RecordsKeeper, a Blockchain-based data security company & also the founder of Toshblocks, A Blockchain Consulting, Development & Training Company. He is a well- known instructor & speaker in Blockchain space and taught more than 10,000 students worldwide spread in 145+ countries. He has also worked on cryptocurrencies, ethereum-based coins & ICO projects for many companies & individuals.Gary Dmitriev Technical AdvisorGary is the Director of Asset Management and Reporting Technology at Fortress Investment Group, where he has spent the last 10 years building a track record of business impact through product implementations in asset management, financial data analysis, and enterprise data management. Beginning his career as a full stack web developer, Gary brings a total of 12 years of experience in the finance industry.    18
     Ken Uryu Technical AdvisorKen graduated from the Boston University School of Management. He was a senior analyst at Merrill Lynch and Goldman Sachs and won top positions in many analyst rankings. After retiring from his analyst position in 2005, he primarily supported the Investment Banking Division as an advisor to Goldman Sachs. Alongside this post, he has been in his current role since the foundation of Minkabu, Inc, a fintech fund focused on combining crowd technology and artificial intelligence in the financial information space.Gary Ross Legal CounselGary J. Ross is the founder & managing attorney of Jackson Ross PLLC. Gary focuses on securities law, VC & PE, corporate governance, & general corporate matters. He represents private companies, angel investors, & VC funds. He has extensive experience advising as to SEC- registered and exempt capital markets transactions, and counsels registered & exempt investment advisers as to compliance issues. Clients include AngelList, Steemit. He is an adjunct professor at Seton Hall Law School, teaching courses in the Financial Services Compliance concentration, including Regulating Depository Banks, Introduction to Corporate Finance, and Regulating Broker- Dealers.                    19
8. THE ROADMAP - PAST, PRESENT, FUTUREinvestFeed Inc was officially registered in September 2014 and currently operates out of New York.8.1. Roadmap Overview    When       Milestone          Details      2014   Partners self- funded operational buildout       ▪ Co-Founders Ronald Chernesky and Andrew Freedman self-fund operational costs to Buildout▪ Developed fully functional desktop platform▪ Developed server farm and basics for trading exchangefunctions       2015   Benzinga FinTech Awards       ▪ Added features and expanded technology.▪ investFeed beta testers rolled onto the platform.▪ Benzinga FinTech Awards: Gala Finalist for most disruptive'Best Use of The Crowd Platform' for investors.▪ Official beta launch        2016    Organic Growth      ▪ Official Global Launch: iOS, Android, and desktop all live▪ Full Brokerage Integration: Robinhood, TD Ameritrade,E*Trade, Scottrade, Fidelity, TradeStation, Options House,and others▪ Portfolio management: Sync all your accounts and trackyour portfolio performance in one place. Intelligently compare your portfolio to others like you and privately or publicly share your portfolio     20
               When       Milestone          Details      2017   Revenue Generated and Strategic Partnerships  ▪ Career Profiles: allows users to create profiles for deep relationship building▪ Featured Feeds: We built a major solution for companies to advertise natively in our "featured feed" video module. This enables our users to view their videos and directly purchase shares in their company without having to leave investFeed.▪ Launch of integrated wallet system (pending)▪ Crowdsourced Portfolio Advice and Recommendations(pending)▪ Premium Subscriptions: Advanced portfolio and socialtools (pending)▪ Premium API: Institutional and hedge fund access(pending)▪ Brokerage Integration: Integrate with 200+ leading cryptobrokerages and personal investing apps (pending)▪ Blockchain-based data feeds & Analytics (etherscan)(pending)▪ Sentiment analytics for cryptocurrency markets (pending)▪ Charting and technical analysis capabilities (pending)       2018         Scale           ▪ This is our year to fully scale the platform focused on user acquisition. We have already built out virality features and functionality similar to Snapchat and Whatsapp for mass market adoption▪ Additional functionalities to support the core features▪ The test environment will be updated with the first beta release for further testing on the Ethereum test network▪ The launch of the merchant platform, GUI and eye candy improvements▪ Generate user documentation     21
8.2. New Feature Development ScheduleThis maps out our short and medium-term development plan for our cross platform (Browser, Native iOS, Native Android) offering.        Time Frame Features Status              Q3 - Q4 2017Improved Social Networking capabilitiesCurrently Underway                Cross platform Live streaming feeds andchannels for all current and upcoming cryptocurrencies and projects based on currency ticker or project nameCurrently Underway.Transitioning from US equities to Blockchain cryptocurrencies, assets, and projects             Fundamental cryptocurrency market dataCurrently Planning             Q1 - Q2 2018BETA PRODUCT LAUNCHPlanned             Trending assets and Watchlist signalsPlanned             Wallet and Exchange integration     FEED Token marketplace rolloutPlanned        Planned             Q3 - Q4 2018Advanced trader toolsPlanned        22
9. TOKEN SALE TIMELINE 9.1. About Token SaleWe are launching an open Ether (ETH) capped token sale to raise funds for the investFeed project to enable us to add more features in the platform. We will be raising minimum 1,500 Ethers and maximum 28,000 Ethers (both inclusive) during the token sale & presale. The number of tokens issued per Ether will depend on the Ethers raised as per below table. You can buy FEED Tokens using any amount of Ethers including a fraction of Ethers like 0.0023 ETH. We will be offering a discount to early contributors which will decay with number of Ethers purchased during the token sale. So, the earlier you purchase, the better the token price you will receive. You can also join us in the pre-sale by contacting us directly with a minimum commitment.9.2. Token Sale Plan           Presale Begins and Countdown Timer begins for public ICO sale~ 23 June 2017          Token Sale Start Date & Time:23 July 2017, 9 AM UTC          Token Sale End Date & Time:7 August 2017, 9 AM UTC          Token Sale Duration in Days:15 Days          Maximum Funding Cap in Ethers:28,000 Ethers          Minimum Funding Target in Ether:1,500 Ethers            Token Price:Slabs based on contributionreceived          Refund if Token Sale Fails to achieve the minimum target?Yes, only if crowd sale fails          Token IssuanceInstantly. But will be transferable by the buyers or outside only after successful crowd sale.          Escrow for the raised fund?Yes. Ethereum Multisig 3/4 Wallet.      23
     9.2. Token Step Pricing & Discount in Ethers     # Ether committed     Stage FEEDs/Ether      1     0-21,000 Ethers       Presale       Discount given      # Ether committed (Including presale)    Stage Tokens/Ether       1  0-24,500 Ethers      Token Sale    10,000 FEED     2  24,500-28,000 Ethers     Token Sale    9,000 FEED     3  28,000 Ethers +      Token Sale    Sale will stop 9.3. Token Distribution      Pre-sale (23 June - 23 July)       Up to 21,000 Ethers     ICO Sale: (23 July - 7 Aug)     28,000 Ethers max including the Presale stage     InvestFeed Platform  2.5% of the sold tokens for signup bonuses, etc. Community growth via leveraging free access to basic features and marketplace capabilities.      Core Team    5% of the sold tokens      Bounty & Rewards       1.5% of the sold tokens     Advisors   2% of the sold tokens 9.4. FEED Token Technical Details          Token NameFEED            Token CompliantERC20          Token Technology PlatformEthereum          Token Decimal Points8          Token Smallest Unit NameFEEDbit          Token SymbolFEED          Token Total SupplyExact amount will be decided by contribution      24
10. FUND ESCROW ARRANGEMENTSWhen the FEED Token sale completes successfully, the FEED Tokens will be enabled for transfer among the members instantly. Tokens can be pre-purchased through the ICO site, or earned through a series of bonus / bounty / referral programs or via the investFeed platform.The funds become available to investFeed under the milestones described under 'Project Funds Release'. To promote trust in the investFeed project and to execute a successful Token sale we have established an escrow arrangement using a Multisig wallet for both Bitcoin & Ether.Ether Multisig Wallet: We will be using standard Ethereum Multisig wallet contract created through the Ethereum/Mist Wallet.Each withdraw from the fund will require 3 out of 4 below signatories to sign the withdrawal transaction. Escrow signatories for both the currencies will be:          Name RoleLinkedIn Profile Ethereum Address                 Ron CherneskyCEO investFeedClick here0xf1BdA8f06191bC29F46d0 ee3CBF68555A478a217                       Drew FreedmanCTO investFeedClick here0x22283B7315dd4B1741676 e092279fc4F46ecC003               Toshendra SharmaICO AdvisorClick here0x72Bbe344986351A0C4E8 99D655E81DE8f64E9794                Gary DmitrievTechnical AdvisorClick here0x6c750dA8df323D53eed6 812a7AFB834B0752e94c          25
 Toshendra Sharma & Gary Dmitriev will each receive 0.5% of the amount raised at ICO in ETH but with the minimum of 20 Ethers each. This will be treated in the P&L as part of 'cost of raising capital' and the escrow fees shall be paid out the day after the ICO has officially closed.They shall be calculated as follows:▪ Total raised during ICO x 1% = total escrow fees (of which 1/2 are paid toToshendra & 1/2 to Gary the day following ICO closing).The remaining balance will constitute the funds the Escrow Signatories will release to the project as outlined below. 26
10.1. Project Funds ReleaseThe ICO Balance after escrow fees will be released via Multisig on a 3 of 4 arrangement. Funds will be released in 3 stages when the following milestones are met:1. FEED Token post-Token Sale complete: 50% funds released2. Milestone 1: Application Infrastructure integration complete: 25% funds releaseda. investFeed social network application operable, and connected to underlying market with live price tracking3. Milestone 2: investFeed application live in beta: 25% funds releaseda. investFeedproductliveinbeta,toadesignatedclient’srequirementsShould the circumstance arise where the first milestone has not been met after a period of 90 days following completion of the ICO, the REMAINING funds raised will be returned to the purchasers.10.2. Project Funds UsageThe proceeds of the funds raised will be used to deliver on our goal of disrupting the cryptocurrency industry and create a single gateway to the market that is open, transparent, and rewards-based for all our users and contributors. This will entail additional human resources within the team to deliver on our development roadmap. Most of the funds raised will be allocated to this development task.We also intend to allocate 20-25% of the raise to marketing in order to drive community awareness and grow our community user base. This budget will go towards the creation of marketing resources, both in terms of content and ensuring we have the appropriate human resources to drive our brand via the appropriate channels.Over and above development and marketing expenditure, investFeed will incur some administration, legal and other operating expenses which will form part of the usage budget. 27
11. OUR PROMISEWe want to grow a community of users that echoes our philosophy. If you believe in an open, transparent, rewards based alternative to the current status quo, then join us. You will find yourself among friends. We want to put you, the members of our community, back in the driving seat. In control of your privacy. In control of your investments. In control of your earning potential.  Our community is at the heart of investFeed.Without you, we are nothing. ~ CEO, Ronald Chernesky 28 
12. DISCLAIMERNOT AN OFFER TO SOLICIT SECURITIES AND RISKS ASSOCIATED WITH FEED AND THE INVESTFEED APPLICATIONLast Updated June 21, 2017This document is for informational purposes only and does not constitute an offer or solicitation to sell shares or securities in investFeed, Inc. or any related or associated company. Any such offer or solicitation would only be made by a confidential offering memorandum and in accordance with applicable securities and other laws. None of the information or analyses presented are intended to form the basis for any investment decision, and no specific recommendations are intended. Accordingly, this document does not constitute investment advice or counsel or solicitation for investment in any security. This document does not constitute or form part of, and should not be construed as, any offer for sale or subscription of, or any invitation to offer to buy or subscribe for, any securities, nor should it or any part of it form the basis of or be relied on in any connection with, any contract or commitment whatsoever. InvestFeed expressly disclaims any and all responsibility for any direct or consequential loss or damage of any kind whatsoever arising directly or indirectly from: (i) reliance on any information contained in this document, (ii) any error, omission or inaccuracy in any such information or (iii) any action resulting therefrom.The investFeed Token, or “FEED”, is a cryptographic token used by the investFeed application.FEED is not a cryptocurrency.At the time of this writing, (i) with the exception of being used to place ads on the investFeed platform, FEED cannot be exchanged for goods or services, (ii) FEED has no  29
known uses outside the investFeed application, and (iii) FEED cannot be traded on any known exchanges.FEED is not an investment.There is no guarantee – indeed there is no reason to believe – that the FEED you purchase will increase in value. It may – and probably will at some point – decrease in value. Those who do not actually use their FEED honestly and fairly may lose their right to use FEED and may lose their FEED to those that do use FEED honestly and fairly.FEED is not evidence of ownership or right to control.Controlling FEED does not grant its controller ownership or equity in investFeed, or the investFeed application. FEED does not grant any right to participate in the control, direction or decision making of investFeed or the investFeed application. 30
13. RISK DISCLOSURESRisk of Losing Access to FEED Due to Loss of CredentialsThe purchaser’s FEED may be associated with an investFeed account until they are distributed to the purchaser. The investFeed account can only be accessed with login credentials selected by the purchaser. The loss of these credentials will result in the loss of FEED. Best practices dictate that purchasers safely store credentials in one or more backup locations geographically separated from the working location.Risks Associated with the Ethereum ProtocolFEED and the investFeed application are based on the Ethereum protocol. As such, any malfunction, unintended function, unexpected functioning of or attack on the Ethereum protocol may cause the investFeed application or FEED to malfunction or function in an unexpected or unintended manner. Ether, the native unit of account of the Ethereum protocol may itself lose value in ways similar to FEED, and also other ways. More information about the Ethereum protocol is available at http://www.ethereum.org.Risks Associated with Purchaser CredentialsAny third party that gains access to or learns of the purchaser’s login credentials or private keys may be able to dispose of the purchaser’s FEED. To minimize this risk, the purchaser should guard against unauthorized access to their electronic devices.Risk of Unfavorable Regulatory Action in One or More JurisdictionsBlockchain technologies have been the subject of scrutiny by various regulatory bodies around the world. The functioning of the investFeed application and FEED could be impacted by one or more regulatory inquiries or actions, including the licensing of or restrictions on the use, sale, or possession of digital tokens like FEED, which could impede, limit or end the development of the investFeed application.  31
Risk of Alternative, Unofficial investFeed ApplicationFollowing the Crowdsale and the development of the initial version of the FEED platform, it is possible that alternative applications could be established, which use the same open source code and protocol underlying the investFeed application. The official investFeed application may compete with these alternative, unofficial FEED-based applications, which could potentially negatively impact the investFeed application and FEED, including its value.Risk of Insufficient Interest in the investFeed Application or Distributed ApplicationsIt is possible that the investFeed application will not be used by a large number of businesses, individuals, and other organizations and that there will be limited public interest in the creation and development of distributed applications. Such a lack of interest could negatively impact FEED and the investFeed application.Risk that the investFeed Application, As Developed, Will Not Meet the Expectations of investFeed or the PurchaserThe investFeed application is presently under development and may undergo significant changes before release. Any expectations or assumptions regarding the form and functionality of the investFeed application or FEED (including participant behavior) held by investFeed or the purchaser may not be met upon release, for any number of reasons including mistaken assumptions or analysis, a change in the design and implementation plans and execution of the investFeed application.Risk of Theft and HackingHackers or other groups or organizations or countries may attempt to interfere with the investFeed application or the availability of FEED in any number of ways, including service attacks, Sybil attacks, spoofing, smurfing, malware attacks, or consensus based attacks. 32
Risk of Security Weaknesses in the FEED Application Core Infrastructure SoftwareThe investFeed application consists of open source software that is based on other open source software. There is a risk that the investFeed team or other third parties may intentionally or unintentionally introduce weaknesses or bugs into the core infrastructural elements of the investFeed application interfering with the use of or causing the loss of FEED.Risk of Weaknesses or Exploitable Breakthroughs in the Field of CryptographyAdvances in cryptography, or technical advances such as the development of quantum computers, could present risks to cryptocurrencies and the investFeed platform, which could result in the theft or loss of FEED.Risk of FEED Mining AttacksAs with other decentralized cryptographic tokens and cryptocurrencies, the blockchain used for the investFeed application is susceptible to mining attacks, including double- spend attacks, majority mining power attacks, “selfish-mining” attacks, and race condition attacks. Any successful attacks present a risk to the investFeed application, FEED, and expected proper execution and sequencing of Ethereum contract computations. Despite the efforts of the investFeed team, the risk of known or novel mining attacks exists.Risk of Lack of Adoption or Use of the investFeed ApplicationWhile FEED should not be viewed as an investment, it may have value over time. That value may be limited if the investFeed application lacks use and adoption. If this becomes the case, there may be few or no markets following the launch of the platform, potentially having an adverse impact on FEED. 33
Risk of an Illiquid Market for FEEDThere very well may never be a secondary market for FEED. There are currently no exchanges upon which FEED would trade. If ever exchanges do develop, they will likely be relatively new and subject to poorly understood regulatory oversight. They may, therefore, be more exposed to fraud and failure than established, regulated exchanges for other products and have a negative impact on FEED.Risk of Uninsured LossesUnlike bank accounts or accounts at some other financial institutions, funds held using the investFeed application or Ethereum network are generally uninsured. In the event of any loss, there is no public insurer, such as the FDIC, or private insurer, to offer recourse to the purchaser.Risk of Dissolution of the investFeed ProjectIt is possible that, due to any number of reasons, including an unfavorable fluctuation in the value of Ether, development issues with the investFeed application, the failure of business relationships, or competing intellectual property claims, the investFeed project may no longer be viable as a business or otherwise and may dissolve or fail to launch.Risk of Malfunction in the investFeed ApplicationIt is possible that the investFeed application malfunctions in an unfavorable way, including one that results in the loss of FEED.Unanticipated RisksCryptographic Tokens are a new and untested technology. In addition to the risks discussed in this White Paper, there are risks that the investFeed team cannot anticipate. Further risks may materialize as unanticipated combinations or variations of the discussed risks or the emergence of new risks. 34
