AbstractWe present a protocol for payments across payment sys- tems. It enables secure transfers between ledgers and allows anyone with accounts on two ledgers to cre- ate a connection between them. Ledger-provided es- crow removes the need to trust these connectors. Con- nections can be composed to enable payments between any ledgers, creating a global graph of liquidity or Interledger.Unlike previous approaches, this protocol requires no global coordinating system or blockchain. Transfers are escrowed in series from the sender to the recipient and executed using one of two modes. In the Atomic mode, transfers are coordinated using an ad-hoc group of notaries selected by the participants. In the Univer- sal mode, there is no external coordination. Instead, bounded execution windows, participant incentives and a “reverse” execution order enable secure payments be- tween parties without shared trust in any system or insti- tution.1 IntroductionSending money today within any single payment system is relatively simple, fast and inexpensive. However, mov- ing money between systems is cumbersome, slow and costly, if it is possible at all.Digital payment systems use ledgers to track accounts and balances and to enable local transfers between their users. Today, there are few connectors facilitating pay- ments between these ledgers and there are high barriers to entry for creating new connections. Connectors are not standardized and they must be trusted not to steal the sender’s money.In this paper, we present a protocol for interledger pay- ments that enables anyone with accounts on two ledgers to create connections between them. It uses ledger- provided escrow—conditional locking of funds—to al- low secure payments through untrusted connectors.Any ledger can integrate this protocol simply by enabling escrowed transfers. Unlike previous approaches, our pro- tocol does not rely on any global coordinating system or ledger for processing payments—centralized [10] or de- centralized [15, 17, 19].Our protocol lowers the barriers to facilitating interledger payments. Connectors compete to provide the best rates and speed. The protocol can scale to handle unlimited payment volume, simply by adding more connectors and ledgers. Composing connectors into chains enables pay- ments between any ledgers and give small or new pay- ment systems the same network effects as the most es- tablished systems. This can make every item of value spendable anywhere—from currencies to commodities, computing resources and social credit.Our protocol provides:• Secure payments through any connector using ledger-provided escrow.• The sender of a payment is guaranteed a crypto- graphically signed receipt from the recipient, if the payment succeeds, or else the return of their es- crowed funds.• Two modes of executing payments: In the Atomic mode, transfers are coordinated by an ad-hoc group of notaries selected by the participants to ensure all transfers either execute or abort. The Univer- sal mode instead uses bounded execution windows and incentives to remove the need for any mutually trusted system or institution.A Protocol for Interledger PaymentsStefan Thomas & Evan Schwartz{stefan,evan}@ripple.com
                                                                                                                                                                                                        The following sections describe our protocol in greater depth. Section 2 introduces the core concepts of the protocol, including the actors involved and the need for ledger-provided escrow. Section 3 presents the Atomic mode. Section 4 presents the Universal mode. Sequence diagrams and the formal protocol specifications can be found in the Appendix.2 Interledger PaymentsA ledger may be used to track anything of value—from currency or stocks to physical goods and titles—and may be centralized or decentralized [17]. As illustrated in Figure 1, payments between accounts in the same sys- tem are accomplished with a simple book transfer.the payment correctly. This severely limits the set of in- stitutions that can act as connectors, resulting in a highly uncompetitive and disconnected global payment system.Ledger-provided escrow guarantees the sender that their funds will only be transferred to the connector once the ledger receives proof that the recipient has been paid. Es- crow also assures the connector that they will receive the sender’s funds once they complete their end of the agree- ment.             Figure 1: Book transferA connector is a system that facilitates interledger payments by coordinating book transfers on multiple ledgers. Connectors can also translate between different protocols used by these ledgers. As illustrated in Figure 2, connector Chloe accepts a transfer into her account on one ledger in exchange for a transfer out of her account on another ledger.Figure 4: The transfers to the connector and recipient are either executed or aborted togetherThe simple arrangement illustrated here can be extended into arbitrarily long chains of connectors to facilitate payments between any sender and any recipient. This brings the small-world network effect (commonly known as the “six degrees of separation”) [3, 21] to payments and creates a global graph of liquidity or Interledger.2.1 Byzantine and Rational ActorsA truly open protocol for payments cannot rely on highly trusted actors for security. It must lower the barriers to participation through built-in protections against poten- tially faulty, self-interested, or malicious behavior by the participants.We use the Byzantine, Altruistic, Rational (BAR) model introduced by [2] for categorizing participants. Byzan-Figure 2: Connector controls accounts on two ledgersThe problem with existing payment protocols is that the sender must trust the connector to follow through on pay- ing the intended recipient. Nothing technically prevents connectors from losing or stealing money, so they must be bound by reputation and legal contracts to complete2Figure 3: Funds are escrowed by the sender and connec- tor on their respective ledgers                                                         
tine actors may deviate from the protocol for any reason, ranging from technical failure to deliberate attempts to harm other parties or simply impede the protocol. Altru- istic actors follow the protocol exactly. Rational actors are self-interested and will follow or deviate from the protocol to maximize their short and long-term benefits.We assume all actors in the payment are either Rational or Byzantine. Protocols that rely on highly trusted actors effectively assume all to be Altruistic—or bound by fac- tors external to the protocol. Assuming the actors to be self-interested or malicious requires the protocol to pro- vide security even when participants are bound only by the algorithm itself.We assume that, as Rational actors, ledgers and connec- tors may require some fee to incentivize their participa- tion in a payment. These fees may be paid in the flow of the payment, or out of band. In this paper, we will only discuss the details of fees necessary to mitigate risks and attacks specific to interledger payments.While ledgers may be Byzantine, we do not attempt to introduce fault-tolerance—protection against accidental or malicious errors—for participants who hold accounts with such a ledger. Ledgers themselves can be made Byzantine fault-tolerant [15, 17, 19], and participants can choose the ledgers with which they hold accounts. We only seek to isolate participants who hold accounts on non-faulty ledgers from risk.We assume that connectors will agree to participate in a payment only if they face negligible or manageable risk for doing so, and that they will charge fees accord- ingly. Connectors will only deliver money on a destina- tion ledger if doing so benefits them directly.Any of the participants in a payment may attempt to over- load or defraud any of the other actors involved. Thus, escrow is needed to make secure interledger payments.2.2 Cryptographic EscrowLedger-provided escrow enables secure interledger pay- ments by isolating each participant from the risks of fail- ure or malicious behavior by others involved in the pay- ment. It represents the financial equivalent of the states in the Two-Phase Commit Protocol [13, 14].Providing escrowed transfers is the main requirement for ledgers to enable secure interledger payments.All participants rely upon their ledgers to escrow funds and release them only when a predefined condition is met. The sender is assured by their ledger that their funds are transferred only upon delivery of a non-repudiableacknowledgement that the recipient has received their payment. The recipient is assured by their ledger that they will be paid when they provide such an acknowl- edgement. Connectors also use their ledgers’ escrow to protect themselves from risk.Cryptographic signatures are a simple way for ledgers to securely validate the outcome of the external conditions upon which a transfer is escrowed. Any one-way func- tion can be used [18]. Using asymmetric cryptography, the ledger escrows funds pending the presentation of a valid signature for a pre-defined public key and message or hash. The ledger can then easily validate the signature when it is presented and determine if the condition has been met.Figure 5: Transfer statesFigure 5 illustrates the states of a transfer. First, a trans- fer is proposed to the participants, but no changes are made to the ledger. Once affected account holders have authorized the transfer, the ledger checks that funds are available and that all of its rules and policies have been satisfied. The ledger places the funds in escrow and the transfer is prepared. If the execution condition e is ful- filled, the transfer is executed. If any of the checks fail, or if an abort condition e′ is fulfilled, the transfer is aborted and the escrowed funds are returned to their originator.3 Atomic Interledger PaymentsInterledger payments consist of transfers on different ledgers. If the payment partially executes, at least one of the participants loses money. Thus, participants want atomicity—a guarantee that all of the component trans- fers will either execute or that all will be aborted.Executing transfers atomically across multiple ledgers requires a transaction commit protocol. The simplest such protocol is the Two-Phase Commit, in which all systems involved first indicate their readiness to com- plete the transaction, and then execute or abort based on whether all of the other systems have agreed. The ba- sic form of that protocol uses a transaction manager to collect the responses of the various system and dissem- inate the decision. Fault tolerance can be added to the Two-Phase Commit by replacing the single transaction          3
                                                              manager with a group of coordinators that use a consen- sus algorithm to agree on the outcome of the payment [14].The Atomic execution mode uses a Byzantine fault- tolerant agreement algorithm amongst an ad-hoc group of coordinators or notaries to synchronize the execution of the component transfers. Additionally, it guarantees that the sender receive a cryptographically signed pay- ment receipt from the recipient if funds are transferred.Figure 6 shows a payment through a chain of participants P and ledgers L. There are n participants in P, such that |P| = n. The sender is the first participant p1 and the recipient is the last participant pn. The connectors C are participants p2 through pn−1, such that {pi ∈ C | C ⊂ P∧i ∈ Z+ ∧1 < i < n}. The payment consists of n−1 book transfers B on n − 1 ledgers, such that |B| = |L| = n − 1. The first participant, the sender p1 , has an account on ledger l1 . The last participant, the recipient pn , has an account on ledger ln−1. Each connector pi ∈ C has accounts on ledgers li−1 and li and facilitates payments between them.3.1 NotariesIn the Atomic mode, transfers are coordinated by a group of notaries N that serve as the source of truth regarding the success or failure of the payment. They take the place of the transaction manager in a basic Two-Phase Com- mit. Importantly, notaries are organized in ad-hoc groups for each payment and our protocol does not require one globally trusted set of notaries.All of the escrow conditions for the book transfers B comprising the payment must depend on the notaries ei- ther sending a D Execute or D Abort message. If the es- crow conditions were based solely on a message from N, however, faulty notaries could cause the transfers to execute before the final transfer to the recipient is L Prepared. [11].Notaries N must only agree on the D Execute or D Abort messages if they have received a signed receipt, the R ReceiptSignature, from the recipient pn before a time- out t. The recipient’s signature provides non-repudiable proof that they have been paid. The recipient pn signs the receipt once the transfer into their account is L Prepared and escrowed pending their signature.To ensure all of the transfers B can be executed atom- ically, all of the execution conditions E must depend on the D Execute message from the notaries and the R ReceiptSignature from the recipient:∀e ∈ E : e = R ReceiptSignature ∧ D Execute (1)The abort conditions E′ for each transfer in B are de- pendent only on the abort message D Abort. Receipt of a message fulfilling the abort condition e′i where {i ∈ Z+ ∧ i < n} causes the ledger li to immediately tran- sition the L Proposed or L Prepared transfer bi to the L Aborted state and release the funds to the originator.∀e′ ∈E′ :e′ =D Abort (2) 3.2 Fault ToleranceThe Atomic mode only guarantees atomicity when no- taries N act honestly. Like all other participants, we as- sume notaries are either rational or Byzantine. Rational actors can be incentivized to participate with a fee.Byzantine notaries, however, could sign both D Execute and D Abort messages, communicate them to different ledgers and cause some transfers to be executed and other to be aborted. In order to protect against this, we must set a fault-tolerance threshold f . This means that the out- come of the agreement protocol will be correct so long as there are no more than f Byzantine notaries in N.Figure 6: Payment chain                  4
If f =0,weonlyneedasinglenotaryN={N1}andthe D Execute and D Abort messages are simply signatures by that notary N1.If f ≥ 1, notaries use a Byzantine fault-tolerant (BFT) agreement protocol. Using the method from [14, 16], a BFT replication algorithm, such as PBFT [8] or Tan- garoa, a BFT version of Raft [9], can be simplified into a binary agreement protocol.The minimum number of processes required to tolerate f Byzantinefaultsis|N|=3f+1asshownby[5].The D Execute and D Abort messages are collections of signatures from some representative subset Nrep such that Nrep ⊆ N and |Nrep| = f +1 vouching for the outcome of the agreement protocol.3.3 TimeoutTo ensure that funds cannot be held in escrow forever, even in the case of failure, notaries N enforce a timeout t. The recipient pn must submit the R ReceiptSignature to the notaries N before t is reached, or the payment will be aborted and the escrowed funds returned. t must be sufficient to account for the duration of the phases of the protocol leading up to Execution.3.4 Phases of the ProtocolBefore a payment can occur, the sender p1 must find a suitable set of connectors C forming a path to the recip- ient pn. Connectors have an interest in making their liq- uidity information available in order to attract payment flows. The problems of minimum-cost and multicom- modity flow have been studied extensively in the context of planning [1, 7, 20].In the following, we assume that a path has already been chosen and the exchange rates and any fees quoted by the connectors in C are known.Appendix A.1 illustrates the phases of the protocol, ex- cluding Notary Selection and Notary Setup.3.4.1 Notary SelectionNotaries are selected by the participants P.For each candidate fault tolerance threshold fc where fc ∈ Z+ ∧ fc < fmax and fmax is the sender’s maximum fault tolerance threshold, the sender requests the set of all notaries trusted at the given fault tolerance threshold fcfrom each participant p, Np(fc) and calculates the can- didate set Nc(fc) at threshold fc as the intersection of these sets. Each p ∈ P chooses Np( fc) such that they be- lieve that there is no Byzantine subset Nevil where Nevil ⊆ Np(fc),|Nevil| > f which will collude against them.∀ fc ∈ Z+ ∧ fc < fmax : Nc( fc) =   Np( fc) (3) p∈PFinally the sender chooses a fault tolerance threshold f and a corresponding set of notaries N such that N ⊆ Nc(f)∧|N| ≥ 3f +1. If no such set exists, the sender cannot rely on the Atomic mode and must instead use the Universal mode as described in Section 4.3.4.2 ProposalIn the proposal phase, the sender p1 notifies each connec- tor{pi |i∈Z+∧1<i<n}aboutthethebooktransfers bi−1 and bi in the upcoming payment. Upon receiving the proposal, each connector pi will verify the proposed spread between the payments matches its exchange rate, charge its fee and store the payment details. pi accepts the terms of the book transfers bi−1 and bi and the sender p1 proceeds to the next phase.3.4.3 PreparationUnlike in a basic Two-Phase Commit, book transfers {bi ∈B|i∈Z+∧1<i<n}arepreparedinsequence from b1 to bn−1. Each connector is only willing to es- crow their funds if they know funds have already been escrowed for them.The sender p1 first authorizes and sends the instruction to prepare the first transfer b1 on l1. p1 then requests that the first connector p2 prepare b2 on l2. The connector p2 is comfortable preparing b2 because b1 is prepared and the funds have been escrowed by l1. Similarly, each connector pi prepares transfer bi once it is notified that li−1 has prepared bi−1 and escrowed the corresponding funds.3.4.4 ExecutionOnce the last book transfer bn−1 has been prepared and the funds escrowed, the recipient pn must sign the re- ceipt before the timeout t. pn is comfortable signing the receipt because they know that doing so will fulfill the condition of the escrowed funds waiting for them on ln−1. pn submits the R ReceiptSignature to the notaries      5
N, who then run the agreement protocol (see Section 3.2) to decide whether the payment should execute.If N agree that the R ReceiptSignature was received in time, they submit it and a signed D Execute message to all participants P. Each participant {pi ∈ P | i ∈ Z+ ∧1 < i ≤ n} submits the R ReceiptSignature and D Execute message to li−1 to execute bi−1 and claim the funds they are due.If N agree that the payment timed out, they submit the a signed D Abort message to P. Each participant { p j ∈ P | j∈Z+∧1≥ j<n}submitstheD Abortmessagetoljand reclaims its escrowed funds.3.5 CorrectnessThe Atomic mode of the protocol inherits the assump- tions and level of fault-tolerance from the Byzantine agreement protocol used amongst the notaries. For the purpose of this section, we assume the notaries use PBFT [8].Given the assumptions in [8] we require no additional assumptions.3.5.1 SafetySafety means that if one non-faulty ledger transitions its transfer to the L Executed state, then no non-faulty ledger will transition a transfer belonging to the same payment to the L Aborted state and vice versa. If live- ness also holds, all transfers will eventually be executed or all aborted.Given the safety of the consensus algorithm used by the notaries, we know that all ledgers will only receive one of either: f + 1 D Execute, or f + 1 D Abort messages from notaries. A correct ledger only executes the transfer when it has received f + 1 D Execute messages which precludes the possibility that any other correct ledger has aborted their transfer. Equally, a correct ledger only aborts the transfer when it has received f + 1 D Abort messages which precludes the possibility that any other correct ledger has received f + 1 D Execute messages and aborted their transfer.3.5.2 LivenessLiveness means that every non-faulty ledger connected to at least one non-faulty, rational participant will even- tually execute or abort its transfer.As mentioned in Section 3.3, the notaries will initiate their agreement protocol spontaneously after a timeout t. From the liveness property of the underlying agree- ment protocol, we know that the notaries will eventually decide to either D Execute or D Abort and broadcast that decision to the participants. Each ledger is connected to at least two participants. If one of these participants is non-faulty, it will forward the decision to the ledger.Note that if notaries could broadcast directly to the ledgers, our protocol could maintain liveness even when all participants are faulty. However, in real world appli- cations, some ledgers use proprietary protocols or private networks, so we cannot rely on the fact that the notaries can reach them directly.If a transfer is in the L Prepared state, at least one of the participants has an interest in seeing the transfer reach a final state, because the escrowed funds would be trans- ferred to them. If this participant is rational they will therefore eventually forward the notaries’ decision. A Byzantine participant in this position may not, but in do- ing so does not hurt anyone else.3.6 FeesEach connector in C incurs some costs and risks for par- ticipating in a payment, which can be priced into the con- nectors’ fees.When trading different assets, connectors in C effectively write the sender p1 an American option [4, 6] which, on exercise, swaps an asset on one ledger for an equivalent asset on another ledger. In addition to the factors con- sidered in standard option pricing, the connector should also account for the following attack in its fee.3.6.1 Liquidity StarvationAn attacker can attempt to temporarily tie up all of a con- nector’s liquidity in payments it knows will fail. This at- tack is rendered uneconomical if the connector sets its fee to cover its costs and the profit it would expect if the payment were successful. Furthermore, connectors, in- cluding those operated by the same entity as a ledger, can prevent their funds from being completely tied up by escalating their fees as a function of the percentage of their total liquidity being held in escrow.                6
4 Universal Interledger PaymentsWhile the Atomic mode uses notaries to ensure proper execution of a payment, the Universal mode relies on the incentives of rational participants instead to eliminate the need for external coordination. It provides safety and liveness for all non-faulty participants connected to only non-faulty ledgers, under an assumption of bounded syn- chrony with a known bound. In Section 4.4.1 we discuss the practical considerations of using Universal mode in a system that does not guarantee bounded synchrony, e.g. the Internet.Appendix A.2 illustrates the phases of the payment in this mode.4.1 Execution OrderIn Universal mode, there are no notaries. The book transfers B must be executed in a specific order to en- sure all participants’ incentives are aligned to execute the payment properly and to ensure delivery of the R ReceiptSignature to the sender p1.The transfers B are escrowed only on the condition of receiving the R ReceiptSignature:∀e ∈ E : e = R ReceiptSignature (4)Instead of having a global timeout, each book transfer in{bi ∈B|i∈Z+∧i<n}hasitsownexpirationtime enforced by the ledger li. After the last book transfer bn−1 is prepared, the recipient pn signs the receipt and presents the R ReceiptSignature directly to their ledger ln−1. If it is before the transfer’s expiration time tn−1, bn−1 will be executed immediately.Once bn−1 is executed and the recipient pn is paid, connector pn−1 has a very strong incentive to pass the R ReceiptSignature back to ln−2, as they have paid out money but have not yet been paid. When each con- nector {pj ∈P| j∈Z+∧1< j<n} learns of the execution of the book transfer bj, they must get the R ReceiptSignature from l j and submit it to l j−1 to claim the money waiting in escrow for them.Thus, the transfers in B are executed in “backwards” or- der, from the recipient pn to the sender p1. Once the first transfer b1 is executed, the sender p1 can get the R ReceiptSignature from their ledger l1.If the last transfer bn−1 times out before pn submits the R ReceiptSignature, all transfers in B will expire and the escrowed funds will be returned to their originator. Thefollowing section discusses expiration times and the mes- sage delay risk connectors must manage.4.2 Message DelayEach book transfer in B must have an expiration time t to ensure liveness. In order for a connector {pi ∈ P | i ∈ Z+ ∧ 1 < i < n} to agree to take part in the payment, they must be able to pass the R ReceiptSignature from ledger li to li−1 and execute bi−1 before it expires. If bi is executed but bi−1 expires, pi loses money. Because bi may execute very close to its expiration time ti, the expiration time ti−1 for transfer bi−1 must be greater than that of bi by some finite time difference ti−1 −ti.This time difference ti−1 − ti must account for the mes- saging delays M(li, pi) from li to pi and M(pi,li−1) from pi to li−1 (which includes the processing delays at pi, li and li−1 respectively) and the clock skew K(li−1,li) be- tween ledgers li−1 and li.ti ≥ti+1 +M(li,pi+1)+M(pi+1,li)+S(li,li+1) (5)The timeout tn−1 for the destination transfer bn−1 is equal to the timeout t in Atomic mode introduced in Section 3.3. That is, it is large enough to allow for the preparation of the transfers and for the recipient to sign and submit the R ReceiptSignature.4.3 CorrectnessFor our analysis of Universal mode, we consider both safety and liveness under bounded synchrony. We define bounded synchrony similar to the definition given in [12] as a system in which there is a known upper bound M on messaging delays between processes and a known upper bound S on clock skew between two nodes. We assume that processing times are negligible and included in M.4.3.1 SafetySafety means that there will be no book transfer {bi ∈ B | i ∈ Z+ ∧ i < n − 1} which expires if bi+1 executed unless li, li+1 or participant pi+1 are faulty.Let bi+1 execute at time φ0. We know that bi+1 was not expired, therefore:φ0 < ti+1 (6)          7
A correct ledger li+1 will send a message ⟨M ExecuteNotify,R ReceiptSignature⟩ to connec- tor pi+1 which will arrive at time φ1:φ1 ≤φ0+M(li,pi+1)The rational connector pi+1 will send a message4.4.1 OptimalTimeoutsIn an asynchronous system, message delays and clock skew are unbounded, so a connector {pi ∈ P | i ∈ Z+∧1<i<n} may lose the race to forward the R ReceiptSignature from li to li−1, causing them to lose money.However, by observing prior performance of the net- work, pi can estimate the probability Pr(ti−1 − ti ≥ M(li, pi+1) + M(pi+1,li) + S(li,li+1)), calculate the value of the risk to them and include it in their fee.As ti−1 − ti becomes larger, the risk decreases. However, the expiration time for each transfer {b j ∈ B | j ∈ Z+ ∧ j < i − 1} also increases. Longer expiration times incur higher fees, because funds may be held in escrow for a longer period. The sender p1 will try to choose ti−1 − tisuch that the total amount of fees is minimized.4.4.2 Robust MessagingThe other participants may collude in an attempt to de- fraud a connector. In order to do so, they must interfere with the messaging as mentioned in the previous section topreventtheconnector{pi ∈P|i∈Z+∧1<i<n} from completing the transfer bi−1 thereby profiting at pi’s expense.The mitigation for this attack varies based on the techni- cal characteristics of each ledger. However, in all cases, it is a type of Denial of Service mitigation. Both connec- tors and ledgers have an interest in establishing reliable communication.4.4.3 Receipt PrivacyThe recipient pn does not have to transfer any money, but we assume that the act of signing the receipt has some external meaning, such as nullifying an existing asset of the recipient (e.g. an invoice) or creating a new liability.To claim the funds escrowed for them, the recipient pn must submit R ReceiptSignature to ln−1 before the trans- fer bn−1 is executed. In an asynchronous system, bn−1 might timeout while this message is in transit.In order to guarantee safety for the recipient then, we must introduce another property of ledgers, ReceiptPri- vacy. A correct ledger that offers ReceiptPrivacy does not disclose a ⟨D Execute, R ReceiptSignature⟩ message (or the R ReceiptSignature contained therein) unless bi is executed successfully.   ⟨M   ExecuteRequest, R   ReceiptSignature⟩ to which will arrive at time φ2.φ2 ≤φ1+M(pi+1,li)(7)ledger li(8)The correct ledger li is guaranteed to execute transfer bi if and only if the message arrives before the timeout ti. However, so far we have expressed all times in terms of li+1’s local clock. In order to ensure that bi is not expired, we must account for clock skew:ti ≥φ2+S(li,li+1) (9) From equations (5), (6), (7), (8) and (9):ti ≥φ2+S(li,li+1)≥ φ1 +M(pi+1,li)+S(li,li+1)≥ φ0 +M(li, pi+1)+M(pi+1,li)+S(li,li+1) ≥ti+1 +M(li,pi+1)+M(pi+1,li)+S(li,li+1)(10)Since li is a correct ledger, it will execute the transfer. A transfer that has been executed on a correct ledger cannot expire, therefore bi cannot expire.4.3.2 LivenessLiveness means that eventually each book transfer {bi ∈ B|i∈Z+∧i<n}onanon-faultyledgerli musteither be L Executed or L Aborted.All book transfers bi have a finite expiry time ti. A cor- rect ledger li will expire transfer bi at time ti unless it has already executed.Therefore after time ti, transfer bi will be either L Executed or L Aborted.4.4 Fault and Attack MitigationIn Section 3.6 we discussed the connector fee in Atomic mode. In Universal mode, there are additional costs that the connector must take into account:        8
If the recipient chooses an honest ledger with Re- ceiptPrivacy, they are not at risk, even in an asyn- chronous system, because their ledger ln−1 will disclose R ReceiptSignature if and only if bn−1 executes.5 ConclusionWe have proposed a protocol for secure interledger pay- ments across an arbitrary chain of ledgers and connec- tors. It uses ledger-provided escrow based on crypto- graphic conditions to remove the need to trust the con- nectors.The Atomic mode of the protocol provides atomicity for payment chains in which the participants can agree upon a group of notaries. The Universal mode uses the in- centives of rational actors to enable practical payments between participants that do not all share trust in any in- stitution or system.Our protocol does not rely on any single system for processing payments, so there is no limit to its scala- bility. Payments can be as fast and cheap as the con- stituent ledgers and connectors allow and transaction de- tails are private to their participants. The separation of concerns and the minimal standardization requirements enable continuous optimization and competition between connectors and between ledgers.Removing the need to trust the connector enables any- one with accounts on two or more ledgers to make con- nections between them. Connectors can be composed to make payments and the financial system more accessi- ble, competitive and resilient. This enables the creation of a global graph of liquidity or Interledger.References[1] AHUJA, R. K., MAGNANTI, T. L., AND ORLIN, J. B. Network flows. Tech. rep., DTIC Document, 1988.[2] AIYER, A. S., ALVISI, L., CLEMENT, A., DAHLIN, M., MAR- TIN, J.-P., AND PORTH, C. Bar fault tolerance for cooperative services. In ACM SIGOPS Operating Systems Review (2005), vol. 39, ACM, pp. 45–58.[3] ALBERT, R., JEONG, H., AND BARABA ́SI, A.-L. Internet: Di- ameter of the world-wide web. Nature 401, 6749 (1999), 130– 131.[4] BLACK, F., AND SCHOLES, M. The pricing of options and cor- porate liabilities. The journal of political economy (1973), 637– 654.[5] BRACHA, G., AND TOUEG, S. Asynchronous consensus and broadcast protocols. Journal of the ACM (JACM) 32, 4 (1985), 824–840.[6] BRENNAN, M. J., AND SCHWARTZ, E. S. The valuation of american put options. Journal of Finance (1977), 449–462.[7] CAI, X., SHA, D., AND WONG, C. Time-varying minimum cost flow problems. European Journal of Operational Research 131, 2 (2001), 352–374.[8] CASTRO, M., LISKOV, B., ET AL. Practical byzantine fault tol- erance. In OSDI (1999), vol. 99, pp. 173–186.[9] COPELAND, C., AND ZHONG, H. Tangaroa: a byzantine fault tolerant raft.[10] DAVIES, D. W., AND PRICE, W. L. Security for computer net- works: and introduction to data security in teleprocessing and electronic funds transfer. John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1989.[11] DOLEV, D., AND STRONG, H. R. Authenticated algorithms for byzantine agreement. SIAM Journal on Computing 12, 4 (1983), 656–666.[12] DWORK, C., LYNCH, N., AND STOCKMEYER, L. Consensus in the presence of partial synchrony. Journal of the ACM (JACM) 35, 2 (1988), 288–323.[13] GRAY, J. Notes on data base operating systems. In Operat- ing Systems, An Advanced Course (London, UK, UK, 1978), Springer-Verlag, pp. 393–481.[14] GRAY,J.,ANDLAMPORT,L.Consensusontransactioncommit. ACM Transactions on Database Systems (TODS) 31, 1 (2006), 133–160.[15] MAZIE`RES, D. The stellar consensus protocol: A federated model for internet-level consensus.[16] MOHAN, C., STRONG, R., AND FINKELSTEIN, S. Method for distributed transaction commit and recovery using byzantine agreement within clusters of processors. In Proceedings of the second annual ACM symposium on Principles of distributed com- puting (1983), ACM, pp. 89–103.[17] NAKAMOTO,S.Bitcoin:APeer-to-Peerelectroniccashsystem.[18] ROMPEL, J. One-way functions are necessary and sufficient for secure signatures. In Proceedings of the twenty-second annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing (1990), ACM, pp. 387– 394.[19] SCHWARTZ,D.,YOUNGS,N.,ANDBRITTO,A.Theripplepro- tocol consensus algorithm. Ripple Labs Inc White Paper (2014).[20] WAGNER, H. M. On a class of capacitated transportation prob- lems. Management Science 5, 3 (1959), 304–318.[21] WATTS, D. J., AND STROGATZ, S. H. Collective dynamics of small-worldnetworks. nature 393, 6684 (1998), 440–442. 9
